<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OWASP_2017_A03 on ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/owasp_2017_a03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OWASP_2017_A03 on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/alerttags/owasp_2017_a03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET ViewState Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10094-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10094-1/</guid>
      <description>An ASP.NET ViewState was disclosed by the application/web server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET ViewState Integrity</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10094-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10094-2/</guid>
      <description>The application does not use a Message Authentication Code (MAC) to protect the integrity of the ASP.NET ViewState, which can be tampered with by a malicious client</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup File Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10095/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10095/</guid>
      <description>A backup of the file was disclosed by the web server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base64 Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10094-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10094-3/</guid>
      <description>Base64 encoded data was disclosed by the application/web server. Note: in the interests of performance not all base64 strings in the response were analyzed individually, the entire response should be looked at by the analyst/security team/developer(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Redirect Detected (Potential Sensitive Information Leak)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10044/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10044/</guid>
      <description>The server has responded with a redirect that seems to provide a large response. This may indicate that although the server sent a redirect it also responded with body content (which may include sensitive details, PII, etc.).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hash Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10097/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10097/</guid>
      <description>A hash was disclosed by the web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Disclosure - Debug Error Messages</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10023/</guid>
      <description>The response appeared to contain common error messages returned by platforms such as ASP.NET, and Web-servers such as IIS and Apache. You can configure the list of common debug messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Disclosure - Sensitive Information in HTTP Referrer Header</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10025/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10025/</guid>
      <description>The HTTP header may have leaked a potentially sensitive parameter to another domain. This can violate PCI and most organizational compliance policies. You can configure the list of strings for this check to add or remove values specific to your environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Disclosure - Sensitive Information in URL</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10024/</guid>
      <description>The request appeared to contain sensitive information leaked in the URL. This can violate PCI and most organizational compliance policies. You can configure the list of strings for this check to add or remove values specific to your environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Disclosure - Suspicious Comments</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10027/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10027/</guid>
      <description>The response appears to contain suspicious comments which may help an attacker. Note: Matches made within script blocks or files are against the entire content not only comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insufficient Site Isolation Against Spectre Vulnerability</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90004-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90004-1/</guid>
      <description>Cross-Origin-Resource-Policy header is an opt-in header designed to counter side-channels attacks like Spectre. Resource should be specifically set as shareable amongst different origins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insufficient Site Isolation Against Spectre Vulnerability</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90004-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90004-2/</guid>
      <description>Cross-Origin-Embedder-Policy header is a response header that prevents a document from loading any cross-origin resources that don&amp;rsquo;t explicitly grant the document permission (using CORP or CORS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insufficient Site Isolation Against Spectre Vulnerability</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90004-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90004-3/</guid>
      <description>Cross-Origin-Opener-Policy header is a response header that allows a site to control if others included documents share the same browsing context. Sharing the same browsing context with untrusted documents might lead to data leak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PII Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10062/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10062/</guid>
      <description>The response contains Personally Identifiable Information, such as CC number, SSN and similar sensitive data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Private IP Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/2/</guid>
      <description>A private IP (such as 10.x.x.x, 172.x.x.x, 192.168.x.x) or an Amazon EC2 private hostname (for example, ip-10-0-56-78) has been found in the HTTP response body. This information might be helpful for further attacks targeting internal systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Referer Exposes Session ID</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/3-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/3-3/</guid>
      <description>A hyperlink pointing to another host name was found. As session ID URL rewrite is used, it may be disclosed in referer header to external hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Leaks Information via &#39;X-Powered-By&#39; HTTP Response Header Field(s)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10037/</guid>
      <description>The web/application server is leaking information via one or more &amp;ldquo;X-Powered-By&amp;rdquo; HTTP response headers. Access to such information may facilitate attackers identifying other frameworks/components your web application is reliant upon and the vulnerabilities such components may be subject to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session ID in URL Rewrite</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/3-1/</guid>
      <description>URL rewrite is used to track user session ID. The session ID may be disclosed via cross-site referer header. In addition, the session ID might be stored in browser history or server logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session ID in URL Rewrite</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/3-2/</guid>
      <description>URL rewrite is used to track user session ID. The session ID may be disclosed via cross-site referer header. In addition, the session ID might be stored in browser history or server logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timestamp Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10096/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10096/</guid>
      <description>A timestamp was disclosed by the application/web server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak Authentication Method</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10105/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10105/</guid>
      <description>HTTP basic or digest authentication has been used over an unsecured connection. The credentials can be read and then reused by someone with access to the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-ChromeLogger-Data (XCOLD) Header Information Leak</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10052/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10052/</guid>
      <description>The server is leaking information through the X-ChromeLogger-Data (or X-ChromePhp-Data) response header. The content of such headers can be customized by the developer, however it is not uncommon to find: server file system locations, vhost declarations, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Debug-Token Information Leak</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10056/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10056/</guid>
      <description>The response contained an X-Debug-Token or X-Debug-Token-Link header. This indicates that Symfony&amp;rsquo;s Profiler may be in use and exposing sensitive data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
