<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frequently Asked Questions on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frequently Asked Questions on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Somethings not working. What should I do?</title>
      <link>/faq/somethings-not-working-what-should-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/somethings-not-working-what-should-i-do/</guid>
      <description>Somethings not working as you expect with ZAP, and you&amp;rsquo;re not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s a bug or a misunderstanding of how ZAP works.
The following steps may well help:
Check for Updates Click on the &amp;lsquo;Manage Add-ons&amp;rsquo; button on the toolbar and then click on the &amp;lsquo;Check for updates&amp;rsquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does ZAP offer community services?</title>
      <link>/faq/does-zap-offer-community-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/does-zap-offer-community-services/</guid>
      <description>Yes, the ZAP team currently offers the following services to the community.
Be Aware The following are all subject to change without notice. We intend for them all to remain as-is over the long term, however, they are primarily intended to be used with ZAP and as such may change is/when required by the project/team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I get a specific feature implemented in ZAP?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-i-get-a-specific-feature-implemented-in-zap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-i-get-a-specific-feature-implemented-in-zap/</guid>
      <description>You have 3 options:
Convince one of the existing ZAP developers that they should implement it Convince someone else to implement it for you Implement it yourself Some of the ZAP core developers are paid to work on ZAP. If you can convince one of the us that we should implement it asap then this will probably be the quickest option as obviously we know the code base well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What &#39;calls home&#39; does ZAP make?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-calls-home-does-zap-make/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-calls-home-does-zap-make/</guid>
      <description>From 2.12.0 all ZAP &amp;lsquo;calls home&amp;rsquo; are made to the zaproxy.org domain.
Check for Updates ZAP makes one request to https://cfu.zaproxy.org to see if ZAP or any of the add-ons are up to date.
The update data is retrieved from the relevant version file in the zap-admin github repo, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are the command line options?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-are-the-command-line-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-are-the-command-line-options/</guid>
      <description>Refer to command line help page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does ZAP test for?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-does-zap-test-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-does-zap-test-for/</guid>
      <description>ZAP supports:
HTTP active and passive scanning. WebSockets passive scanning. For a full list of the HTTP active and passive scan rules see the Alert Details page.
By default ZAP comes with the following (HTTP) scan rules:
Release Active Scan Rules Release Passive Scan Rules Retire.js DOM XSS Active Scan Rule But you can also download and install:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the default directory that ZAP uses?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-is-the-default-directory-that-zap-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-is-the-default-directory-that-zap-uses/</guid>
      <description>The default directory that ZAP uses depends on the OS.
It can be overridden using the -dir command line option.
The default or home directory contains ZAP files added or modified at runtime. Including (but not limited to): config files, add-ons, input files, logs, etc. It is also the save location, for: scripts, active scan policy files, exported contexts, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What versions of Java are supported?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-versions-of-java-are-supported/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-versions-of-java-are-supported/</guid>
      <description>ZAP should be able to run with all/newer Java versions, but might require a minimum for certain ZAP versions:
ZAP 2.7.0 and later requires a minimum of Java 1.8 ZAP 2.0.0 and later requires a minimum of Java 1.7 Previous versions of ZAP also support Java 1.6, the last of those being 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where can I ask ZAP related questions?</title>
      <link>/faq/where-can-i-ask-zap-related-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/where-can-i-ask-zap-related-questions/</guid>
      <description>User Guide The User Guide (which is also included with ZAP) is a good place to start.
User Group The User Group is the best place for questions about using ZAP.
Developer Group The Developer Group is the best place for questions about working on the ZAP source code or extending it via add-ons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where does ZAP put its logs?</title>
      <link>/faq/where-does-zap-put-its-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/where-does-zap-put-its-logs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is ZAP installed?</title>
      <link>/faq/where-is-zap-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/where-is-zap-installed/</guid>
      <description>ZAP is installed in different places depending on the OS.
The install directory contains everything that&amp;rsquo;s bundled with ZAP originally.
Windows 7 / 8 / 10 Underneath the Program Files directory, e.g.
C:\Program Files\OWASP\Zed Attack Proxy - For 64bit installs. C:\Program Files (x86)\OWASP\Zed Attack Proxy - For 32bit installs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why don&#39;t you rewrite ZAP in &lt;my favorite language&gt;?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-dont-you-rewrite-zap-in-my-favorite-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-dont-you-rewrite-zap-in-my-favorite-language/</guid>
      <description>OK, so this question doesn&amp;rsquo;t get asked all the time, but it does come up every so often.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the official response:
Firstly, do you really need ZAP rewritten?
ZAP supports all of the JSR 223 scripting languages, so you can already extend ZAP in a very wide range of scripting languages, including JavaScript, Jython, and Jruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is ZAP not available in my language?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-is-zap-not-available-in-my-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-is-zap-not-available-in-my-language/</guid>
      <description>We rely on people like yourself to translate ZAP into other languages.
If your language is not available then it means that we, the developers, unfortunately don&amp;rsquo;t speak your language well enough to translate it and no one else has volunteered.
However you can help :)
Get in touch with us if you want to translate ZAP into another language, we&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I add my own payloads to active scan rules?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-add-my-own-payloads-to-active-scan-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-add-my-own-payloads-to-active-scan-rules/</guid>
      <description>ZAP doesn&amp;rsquo;t just throw a load of payloads at a target to see what happens :)
The payloads are targeted based on the responses to other payloads so that it hopefully zeros in on specific vulnerabilities.
However there a various options:
Try out the custom payloads add-on which is supported by some of the existing rules Change the existing rules to improve them - this blog post is a good place to start: Hacking ZAP: Active Scan Rules - if you do improve them then please submit pull requests :) Write new rules to do whatever you want - this gives you full control, but could be a bit daunting to start with Tweak the User defined attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I prevent ZAP from sending me 1000s of emails via a &#39;Contact Us&#39; form?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-prevent-zap-from-sending-me-1000s-of-emails-via-a-contact-us-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-prevent-zap-from-sending-me-1000s-of-emails-via-a-contact-us-form/</guid>
      <description>In this case prevention is definitely better than cure.
By default when you use the ZAP spider and active scanner then ZAP will access all of the URLs, forms, and functionality it can find. If one of those results in your application sending emails then someone is going to get a LOT of emails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you speed up scans?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-you-speed-up-scans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-you-speed-up-scans/</guid>
      <description>See this post on the Mozilla Security Blog</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I handle a False Positive?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-i-handle-a-false-positive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-i-handle-a-false-positive/</guid>
      <description>False positives are where ZAP raises alerts for things that are not really vulnerabilities. You should make sure that you understand the potential vulnerability being reported and manually test it before concluding that it is not a real vulnerability.
Please report any false positives that you identify supplying as much information as you can, while obfuscating any sensitive information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I report a False Negative?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-i-report-a-false-negative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-i-report-a-false-negative/</guid>
      <description>False Negatives are where ZAP fails to identify an issue when it should.
Reporting these problems to us for passive scan rules is straightforward - just let us know the full request and/or response that ZAP should have raised the problem for.
Reporting problems with active scan rules is a bit more tricky, as ZAP will potentially send several requests to detect a specific problem and we need to know how your application responded to each one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How often are scan rules updated?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-often-are-scan-rules-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-often-are-scan-rules-updated/</guid>
      <description>Scan rules are defined in add-ons so they can be updated and published whenever they are improved.
However this may be less frequently than you might expect, and there are good reasons for that.
Some security tools focus on finding known vulnerabilities in known applications. New vulnerabilities are being found all of the time so the rules for these tools need to be frequently updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there any danger when scanning with ZAP against a live website (e.g. create/delete/update/corrupt data)?</title>
      <link>/faq/is-there-any-danger-when-scanning-with-zap-against-a-live-website-e-g-create-delete-update-corrupt-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/is-there-any-danger-when-scanning-with-zap-against-a-live-website-e-g-create-delete-update-corrupt-data/</guid>
      <description>Proxying (and therefore passive scanning) requests via ZAP is completely safe and legal, it just allows you to see whats going on.
Spidering is a bit more dangerous. It could cause problems depending on how your application works.
Note that there is an Spider option to not use POST requests - this may be safer but is also likely to reduce the effectiveness of the Spider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Someone is using ZAP to attack my website - what should I do?</title>
      <link>/faq/someone-is-using-zap-to-attack-my-website-what-should-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/someone-is-using-zap-to-attack-my-website-what-should-i-do/</guid>
      <description>ZAP is a free tool designed to help everyone secure their own websites. Unfortunately this means that other people can use it to attack your website as well.
ZAP is not designed to be a covert tool - it uses various variations of &amp;ldquo;ZAP&amp;rdquo; in its attacks, so if someone does use ZAP to attack your site then this should be apparent in your web server logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What should I do if ZAP doesn&#39;t detect a known problem?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-should-i-do-if-zap-doesn-t-detect-a-known-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-should-i-do-if-zap-doesn-t-detect-a-known-problem/</guid>
      <description>If ZAP fails to detect a known problem then please let us know!
Obviously the more information you can give us the better, and the best option would be a simple one page &amp;lsquo;proof of concept&amp;rsquo; in the form of a wavsep test - we can then include those in our regression tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can ZAP scans be inconsistent?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-can-zap-scans-be-inconsistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-can-zap-scans-be-inconsistent/</guid>
      <description>If you run ZAP multiple times against a target then you may well find that the results are subtly different even though the target has not changed.
This is not unusual, and we do not consider this a significant problem.
In our experience it is usually all down to how the application is explored - the traditional and ajax spiders seem to be sensitive to small changes, including things like network speed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I add an application icon for ZAP to Fedora / Gnome 3?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-add-an-application-icon-for-zap-to-fedora-gnome-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-add-an-application-icon-for-zap-to-fedora-gnome-3/</guid>
      <description>As root create a file called /usr/share/applications/owasp-zap.desktop containing:
[Desktop Entry] Name=OWASP ZAP Exec=/opt/owasp/ZAP_2.8.0/zap.sh Icon=/opt/owasp/ZAP_2.8.0/zap.ico Categories=Programming;Security; Type=Application Make sure you correct the paths to match your environment!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I connect to ZAP remotely?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-connect-to-zap-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-connect-to-zap-remotely/</guid>
      <description>By default ZAP will now also only allow connections from the local machine. You can set which IP addresses can connect to the API using the command line:
-config api.addrs.addr.name=123.456.789.123 If you are using ZAP in a completely isolated environment you can allow all IP addresses to connect to the ZAP API using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I use ZAP with a Java application which connects to a web service over SSL?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-use-zap-with-a-java-application-which-connects-to-a-web-service-over-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-use-zap-with-a-java-application-which-connects-to-a-web-service-over-ssl/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ll need to generate a dynamic root CA certificate.
Export it into a file.
Import it in to the JRE cacerts keystore.
Assuming the Java keytool is on the system path, JAVA_HOME is set to the location of a JRE and the Zaproxy CA cert is exported to &amp;ldquo;~/owasp_zap_root_ca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you import POST requests?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-you-import-post-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-you-import-post-requests/</guid>
      <description>GET requests can be easily imported into ZAP using the &amp;ldquo;Import URLs&amp;rdquo; option which is included in ZAP by default. However this only supports GET requests.
If you need to import POST requests, or requests using other HTTP methods like PUT and DELETE, then you have a selection of options:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you start ZAP?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-you-start-zap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-you-start-zap/</guid>
      <description>Again, this depends on the OS:
Windows There are 3 options on Windows:
Via the desktop icon (assuming you selected this option during installation) Via the &amp;lsquo;Start&amp;rsquo; menu: All Programs OWASP Zed Attack Proxy ZAP &amp;lt;version&amp;gt; Via the &amp;lsquo;zap.bat&amp;rsquo; command line script in the installation directory Linux On Linux there&amp;rsquo;s just a &amp;lsquo;zap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can ZAP automatically authenticate via forms?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-zap-automatically-authenticate-via-forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-zap-automatically-authenticate-via-forms/</guid>
      <description>ZAP supports form based authentication, and can automatically (re)authenticate, for example when using the Spider or Active Scanner.
There are a few steps required to set this up which can be performed via either the UI or the API.
Via the UI:
Explore your app while proxying through ZAP Login using a valid username and password Define a Context, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you add a script to ZAP from the command line?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-you-add-a-script-to-zap-from-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-you-add-a-script-to-zap-from-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>To add a script you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use the following command line options (with the values changed to match your requirements of course;)
-config script.scripts.name=&amp;quot;Remove Strict-Transport-Security&amp;quot; -config script.scripts.engine=&amp;quot;Mozilla Zest&amp;quot; -config script.scripts.type=proxy -config script.scripts.enabled=true -config script.scripts.file=&amp;quot;/home/user/scripts/Remove Strict-Transport-Security.zst&amp;quot; See also the FAQ: How do you find out what key to use to set a config value on the command line?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you configure ZAP logging?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-you-configure-zap-logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-you-configure-zap-logging/</guid>
      <description>ZAP logs to a file called &amp;ldquo;zap.log&amp;rdquo; in the ZAP &amp;lsquo;home&amp;rsquo; directory.
The logging is configured by the log4j2.properties file in the same directory.
By default the &amp;lsquo;main&amp;rsquo; logging levels are set to info by these lines:
logger.paros.name = org.parosproxy.paros logger.paros.level = info logger.zap.name = org.zaproxy.zap logger.zap.level = info Changing these to debug (and restarting ZAP) will significantly increase the amount of logging performed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you configure ZAP to test an application on localhost?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-you-configure-zap-to-test-an-application-on-localhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-you-configure-zap-to-test-an-application-on-localhost/</guid>
      <description>ZAP has no problems scanning applications running on localhost, however there are a couple of things you need to be aware of.
By default ZAP listens on port 8080. If your app also listens on 8080 then you&amp;rsquo;ll need to change one of them to listen on a different port - it&amp;rsquo;s probably easier to change ZAP using the Options Local Proxies screen, remember to change your browser&amp;rsquo;s proxy settings as well: Configuring Proxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you find out what key to use to set a config value on the command line?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-you-find-out-what-key-to-use-to-set-a-config-value-on-the-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-you-find-out-what-key-to-use-to-set-a-config-value-on-the-command-line/</guid>
      <description>The ZAP command line allows you to set individual values as follows:
-config api.key=12345 -config connection.timeoutInSecs=60 How can you find out what keys to use to set the values you want?
The keys are a dot notation of the XML used in the config.xml file.
One way to find out which value you need to change is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to connect to an HTTPS site that reports a handshake failure?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-to-connect-to-an-https-site-that-reports-a-handshake-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-to-connect-to-an-https-site-that-reports-a-handshake-failure/</guid>
      <description>First of all try checking the &amp;lsquo;Enable unsafe SSL/TLS renegotiation&amp;rsquo; checkbox in the Certificate Options screen and trying again.
Second check if you&amp;rsquo;ve enabled SSLv2Hello in the outbound connection options. If so, disable SSLv2Hello and reload the content to see if the issue is resolved.
If this doesn&amp;rsquo;t help and an HTTPS site reports a handshake failure then try installing the &amp;lsquo;Java Cryptography Extension (JCE) Unlimited Strength Jurisdiction Policy Files&amp;rsquo;:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What options exist for selective proxying?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-options-exist-for-selective-proxying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-options-exist-for-selective-proxying/</guid>
      <description>There are a number of ways to accomplish selective proxying.
1 - Via a Browser Add-on/Extension Such as FoxyProxy: https://getfoxyproxy.org/ 2 - Via Global Excludes Leveraging Global Excludes you can specify URLs that ZAP should not intercept. 3 - Via a PAC (Proxy Auto-Config) File You can create your own PAC (Proxy Auto-Config) file and dynamically set proxying as you need, then point your browser at it on your harddrive using the file:/// scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why can&#39;t ZAP connect to my web application?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-cant-zap-connect-to-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-cant-zap-connect-to-my-website/</guid>
      <description>This is usually not a ZAP problem.
Is your web application actually running?
Can you connect to it using the IP address rather than the FQDN or hostname?
Can you connect to your application from the same machine using another tool like curl?
If you are using one of the ZAP Docker images then be aware that using Docker will change the networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ZAP be used to test mobile apps?</title>
      <link>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-mobile-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-mobile-apps/</guid>
      <description>Yes, see this video from ZAPCon 2021:
These videos from @SecureCloudDev:
Setting up ZAP for Android Setting up ZAP for iPhone/iPad And these articles:
Intercepting Android traffic using OWASP ZAP - TheZero blog Four Ways to Bypass Android SSL Verification and Certificate Pinning - NetSPI Blog Debugging iOS apps with Zaproxy - Omer Levi Hevroni&amp;rsquo;s blog </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ZAP be used to test my favorite framework or technology?</title>
      <link>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-my-favorite-framework-or-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-my-favorite-framework-or-technology/</guid>
      <description>If you have questions about using ZAP to test your app or site based on a specific framework or technology, please ask in the User Group.
General Single Page Apps -SPAs Vaadin Apps </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ZAP be used to test my favorite vulnerable app?</title>
      <link>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-my-favorite-vulnerable-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-my-favorite-vulnerable-app/</guid>
      <description>If you have questions about using ZAP to test a specific vulnerable app, that isn&amp;rsquo;t answered here, please ask in the User Group.
Damn Vulnerable Web App OWASP Pixi Juice Shop (on another site) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ZAP be used to test Windows 8 Metro apps?</title>
      <link>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-windows-8-metro-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/can-zap-be-used-to-test-windows-8-metro-apps/</guid>
      <description>Yes, and there&amp;rsquo;s an excellent description of how to do that written by Bill Sempf: https://www.sempf.net/post/Pentesting-Windows-8-Metro-Apps-with-Zed-Attack-Proxy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fonts in ZAP look bad on my system - what should I do?</title>
      <link>/faq/fonts-in-zap-look-bad-on-my-system-what-should-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/fonts-in-zap-look-bad-on-my-system-what-should-i-do/</guid>
      <description>This seems to come up on various Linux distros from time to time. For example: https://github.com/zaproxy/zaproxy/issues/3051
The following suggestions may let you work past the issue.
Try starting ZAP from the command line instead of starting it from a shortcut (such as a Plasma/KDE button, dock icon, etc.) Try adding the following to /etc/environment: _JAVA_OPTIONS=&#39;-Dawt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I run ZAP with a high DPI display?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-run-zap-with-a-high-dpi-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-run-zap-with-a-high-dpi-display/</guid>
      <description>If ZAP is displayed in a really tiny window then it&amp;rsquo;s probably because you have a high DPI display.
The solution is easy - use Java 9+
If you need to have multiple versions of Java on Windows then you may find it difficult to specify which one should be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I use the ZAP API in my own regression tests?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-i-use-the-zap-api-in-my-own-regression-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-i-use-the-zap-api-in-my-own-regression-tests/</guid>
      <description>You can use ZAP to perform security regression tests on your own products.
Note that this answer is very basic and WILL need to be improved ;)
You need to have installed Java and ZAP.
To launch ZAP from a Java program you can do something like:
ProcessBuilder pb = new ProcessBuilder(&amp;#34;/home/myuser/fullpath/ZAP 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you easily maximize a tab?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-you-easily-maximize-a-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-you-easily-maximize-a-tab/</guid>
      <description>You can maximise any tab in ZAP by double clicking on it - that tab will now take up all of the ZAP window.
To see the other sets of tabs double click any of the tabs again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can you use ZAP to scan APIs?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-you-use-zap-to-scan-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-you-use-zap-to-scan-apis/</guid>
      <description>ZAP understands API formats like JSON and XML and so can be used to scan APIs.
The problem is usually how to effectively explore the APIs.
There are various options:
If your API has an OpenAPI/Swagger definition then you can import it using the OpenAPI add-on. If your API uses GraphQL then you can explore it using the GraphQL add-on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can ZAP test sites that use certificate pinning?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-can-zap-test-sites-that-use-certificate-pinning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-can-zap-test-sites-that-use-certificate-pinning/</guid>
      <description>Certificate pinning also known as Public Key Pinning &amp;ldquo;is a mechanism for sites to specify which certificate authorities have issued valid certs for that site, and for user-agents to reject TLS connections to those sites if the certificate is not issued by a known-good CA.&amp;rdquo;
Sites that use certificate pinning will typically not be loaded in your browser if you are proxying it through ZAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I see what version of an add-on/extension I have installed?</title>
      <link>/faq/how-do-i-see-what-version-of-an-add-on-extension-i-have-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/how-do-i-see-what-version-of-an-add-on-extension-i-have-installed/</guid>
      <description>There are three ways to do this:
1 - Via the Marketplace Click the Marketplace button in the main toolbar:
The Installed tab now displays a column including the current version. This adds clarity if/when an update is available as the bottom panel displays the details for the update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up ZAP to Test Damn Vulnerable Web App (DVWA)</title>
      <link>/faq/details/setting-up-zap-to-test-dvwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/details/setting-up-zap-to-test-dvwa/</guid>
      <description>Following the steps used to spider/scan DVWA v1.9 at http://localhost/DVWA using ZAP 2.4.3:
Create a new authentication JavaScript/ECMAScript script [1] and replace/set the script contents with the following: function authenticate(helper, paramsValues, credentials) { var loginUrl = paramsValues.get(&amp;#34;Login URL&amp;#34;); var csrfTokenName = paramsValues.get(&amp;#34;CSRF Field&amp;#34;); var csrfTokenValue = extractInputFieldValue(getPageContent(helper, loginUrl), csrfTokenName); var postData = paramsValues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up ZAP to Test OWASP Pixi</title>
      <link>/faq/details/setting-up-zap-to-test-owasp-pixi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/details/setting-up-zap-to-test-owasp-pixi/</guid>
      <description>Notes:
This FAQ is a work in progress as of 2018-June-1 This FAQ contains spoilers: &amp;lt;details&amp;gt; tags have been used to make them expandable and not immediately visible (which should work in most modern browsers). These instructions assume you&amp;rsquo;ve created a user: test@example.com with password: testExample (via http://localhost:8000/register). The following the steps are based on spider/scan of Pixi at http://localhost:8000/ using ZAP 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up ZAP to Test Vaadin Apps</title>
      <link>/faq/details/setting-up-zap-to-test-vaadin-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/details/setting-up-zap-to-test-vaadin-apps/</guid>
      <description>The information in this FAQ is based on details from: This user group thread
The Vaadin framework makes heavy use of JavaScript, so it seems the Ajax Spider is the way to go.
As you work to figure things out and get them configured correctly it makes sense to starting by proxying your browser through ZAP, identifying the http session and then flagging it as the &amp;lsquo;active session&amp;rsquo; before starting the Ajax Spider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What causes: Exception in thread &#39;AWT-EventQueue-0&#39; when loading ZAP on Docked Mac OSX?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-causes-exception-in-thread-awt-eventqueue-0-when-loading-zap-on-docked-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-causes-exception-in-thread-awt-eventqueue-0-when-loading-zap-on-docked-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>As discussed in https://github.com/zaproxy/zaproxy/issues/5469, this issue seems to occur when laptops are docked. (The work around is to un-dock your system.)
This is the same as https://github.com/oracle/visualvm/issues/84 which links to https://bugs.openjdk.java.net/browse/JDK-8223158
This issue is unfortunately outside the control of the ZAP team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What operating systems are supported?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-operating-systems-are-supported/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-operating-systems-are-supported/</guid>
      <description>ZAP should run on all operating systems that support Java 8 - it can even run on a Raspberry Pi!
Note that the ZAP macOS release includes Java 8 (since ZAP 2.5.0) with it and should run without any problems on older Macs like OS X 10.6.8.
If you experience any problems running ZAP then please report them to us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What vulnerability classifications are supported?</title>
      <link>/faq/what-vulnerability-classifications-are-supported/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/what-vulnerability-classifications-are-supported/</guid>
      <description>ZAP includes the following classifications for all of the vulnerabilities it finds wherever possible:
WASC Threat Classification MITRE&amp;rsquo;s Common Weakness Enumeration </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why am I getting blank ZAP windows on Linux?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-am-i-getting-blank-zap-windows-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-am-i-getting-blank-zap-windows-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Java has problems with &amp;rsquo;non standard&amp;rsquo; window managers.
If you have changed from one of the main window managers and are seeing blank windows when you use ZAP then see https://wiki.haskell.org/Xmonad/Frequently_asked_questions#Problems_with_Java_applications.2C_Applet_java_console for potential solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are there missing History IDs?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-are-there-missing-history-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-are-there-missing-history-ids/</guid>
      <description>When you proxy via ZAP you will often see that some of the Ids in the History tab are &amp;lsquo;missing&amp;rsquo;, e.g. it will jump from 1 to 4 etc.
The missing Ids do not refer to &amp;lsquo;hidden&amp;rsquo; requests that ZAP is making.
Instead those requests (which are not sent at all) are generated by ZAP for &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; use only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why has the Quick Scan Attack reported an invalid URL?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-has-the-quick-scan-attack-reported-an-invalid-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-has-the-quick-scan-attack-reported-an-invalid-url/</guid>
      <description>If the Quick Start Attack fails with the message:
Failed to attack the URL, please check that the URL is valid then the first thing to do is check your URL in a browser.
If it works ok then open the ZAP Manual Request Editor, replace the default URL with the one you are trying and send the request.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is an API key required by default?</title>
      <link>/faq/why-is-an-api-key-required-by-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/why-is-an-api-key-required-by-default/</guid>
      <description>Since version 2.4.1 ZAP has required an API key by default in order to invoke API operations that make changes to ZAP. Since version 2.6.0 an API key is required by default in order to invoke any of the API operations. This is a security feature to prevent malicious sites from invoking the ZAP API.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
