<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spider on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spider on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/spider/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spider Automation Framework Support</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/automation/</guid>
      <description>Spider Automation Framework Support This add-on supports the Automation Framework.&#xA;Job: spider The Spider job runs the Traditional Spider. This is fast but does not handle modern applications as effectively.&#xA;It is covered in the video: ZAP Chat 10 Automation Framework Part 4 - Spidering.&#xA;By default this job will spider the first context defined in the environment and so none of the parameters are mandatory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spider dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/dialog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/dialog/</guid>
      <description>Spider dialog This dialog launches the Spider.&#xA;Scope The first tab allows you to select or change the starting point.&#xA;If the starting point is in one or more Contexts then you will be able to choose one of them.&#xA;If that context has any Users defined then you will be able to select one of them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spider tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/tab/</guid>
      <description>Spider tab The Spider tab shows you the set of unique URIs found by the Spider during the scans.&#xA;The &amp;lsquo;New Scan&amp;rsquo; button launches the Spider dialog which allows you to specify exactly what should be scanned.&#xA;The Spider can be run on multiple Sites in parallel and the results for each scan are shown by selecting the scan via the &amp;lsquo;Progress&amp;rsquo; pull-down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Options Spider screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/spider/options/</guid>
      <description>Options Spider screen This screen allows you to configure the Spider options.&#xA;It should be noted that modifying most of these options also affects the running Spider.&#xA;Maximum depth to crawl The parameter defines the maximum depth in the crawling process where a page must be found in order for it to be processed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
