<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Client Side Integration on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Client Side Integration on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Client Side Integration - Passive Scan Rules</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/pscan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/pscan/</guid>
      <description>Client Side Integration - Passive Scan Rules The Client Side Integration add-on supports passive scanning of the data streamed from the browser.
The following rules are included in this add-on:
Information Disclosure - Information in Browser Storage This rule reports any information stored in browser localStorage and sessionStorage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Client Side Integration - AJAX Spider Enhancement</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/ajax-scan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/ajax-scan/</guid>
      <description>Client Side Integration - AJAX Spider Enhancement The AJAX Spider works by launching browsers, clicking links, and filling in fields. It is an effective way to crawl modern web apps but it is not able to directly access the DOM.
The browser extensions included in this add-on can access the DOM and stream specific events back to ZAP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Client Side Integration - Firefox Profile</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/firefox-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/firefox-profile/</guid>
      <description>Client Side Integration - Firefox Profile This add-on creates a Firefox profile called &amp;lsquo;zap-client-profile&amp;rsquo; and sets it as the default profile that ZAP will use. This profile enables the ZAP Firefox extension for all sites.
If you choose to use another profile then you will need to manually approve the ZAP extension for every site you use it for, every time you launch a browser from ZAP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Client Side Integration - Internals</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/internals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/client-side-integration/internals/</guid>
      <description>Client Side Integration - Internals Browser Extension This add-on depends on a ZAP browser extension which runs in Firefox and Chrome - if this extension is not present then this add-on will not be able to do anything.
The browser extension needs to be able to communicate with ZAP, but it must do it in a secure way so that malicious targets cannot abuse the API end points that this add-on defines.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
