<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AJAX Spider on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AJAX Spider on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ajax Spider Automation Framework Support</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/automation/</guid>
      <description>Ajax Spider Automation Framework Support This add-on supports the Automation Framework.
Job: spiderAjax The spiderAjax job allows you to run the Ajax Spider - it is slower than the traditional spider but handles modern web applications well.
- type: spiderAjax # The ajax spider - slower than the spider but handles modern apps well parameters: context: # String: Name of the context to spider, default: first context url: # String: Url to start spidering from, default: first context URL maxDuration: # Int: The max time in minutes the ajax spider will be allowed to run for, default: 0 unlimited maxCrawlDepth: # Int: The max depth that the crawler can reach, default: 10, 0 is unlimited numberOfBrowsers: # Int: The number of browsers the spider will use, more will be faster but will use up more memory, default: 1 browserId: # String: Browser Id to use, default: firefox-headless clickDefaultElems: # Bool: When enabled only click the default element: &amp;#39;a&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;button&amp;#39; and input, default: true clickElemsOnce: # Bool: When enabled only click each element once, default: true eventWait: # Int: The time in millseconds to wait after a client side event is fired, default: 1000 maxCrawlStates: # Int: The maximum number of crawl states the crawler should crawl, default: 0 unlimited randomInputs: # Bool: When enabled random values will be entered into input element, default: true reloadWait: # Int: The time in millseconds to wait after the URL is loaded, default: 1000 tests: - name: &amp;#39;At least 100 URLs found&amp;#39; # String: Name of the test, default: statistic + operator + value type: &amp;#39;stats&amp;#39; # String: Type of test, only &amp;#39;stats&amp;#39; is supported for now statistic: &amp;#39;spiderAjax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AJAX Spider dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/scandialog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/scandialog/</guid>
      <description>AJAX Spider dialog This dialog launches the AJAX Spider.
Scope The first tab allows you to change key features like:
Starting Point The URL which the AJAX spider will start crawling from, or a context (in which case it will be used one of the URLs that are in context as starting point).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options AJAX Spider screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/options/</guid>
      <description>Options AJAX Spider screen This screen allows you to configure the AJAX Spider options. The AJAX Spider is an add-on for a crawler called Crawljax. The add-on sets up a local proxy in ZAP to talk to Crawljax. The AJAX Spider allows you to crawl web applications written in AJAX in far more depth than the native Spider.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AJAX Spider tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/ajax-spider/tab/</guid>
      <description>AJAX Spider tab The AJAX Spider tab shows you the set of unique URIs found by AJAX Spider.
For each request you can see:
The request index - each request is numbered, starting at 1 The request timestamp The HTML method, e.g. GET or POST The URL requested The HTTP response status code A short summary of what the HTTP response code means The length of time the whole request took The size of the response header The size of the response body Any Alerts on the request Any Notes you have added to request Any Tags you have added to request Selecting a requests will display it in the Request tab and Response tab above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
