<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Releases on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Releases on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.11.1</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.11.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.11.1/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.11.1 This release includes an important security fix - users are urged to upgrade asap. For more details refer to the blog post ZAP and Log4Shell.
Changes in Bundled Libraries The following library was updated:
 Log4j 2, 2.14.1 → 2.15.0  Updated Add-Ons All of the add-ons included by default have been updated since the last full release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.11.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.11.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.11.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.11.0 This is the OWASP 20th anniversary bug fix and enhancement release, which requires a minimum of Java 8. Note that a minimum of Java 11 is recommended, especially for high DPI displays.
These release notes do not include all of the changes included in add-ons updated since 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.10.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.10.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.10.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.10.0 This is a 10 year anniversary bug fix and enhancement release, which requires a minimum of Java 8. Note that a minimum of Java 11 is recommended, especially for high DPI displays.
These release notes do not include all of the changes included in add-ons updated since 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.9.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.9.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.9.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.9.0 This is a bug fix and enhancement release, which requires a minimum of Java 8. Note that a minimum of Java 11 is recommended, especially for high DPI displays.
These release notes do not include all of the changes included in add-ons updated since 2.8.0.
Some of the more significant enhancements include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.8.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.8.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.8.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.8.0 This is a bug fix and enhancement release, which requires a minimum of Java 8. Note that a minimum of Java 11 is recommended, especially for high DPI displays.
These release notes do not include all of the changes included in add-ons updated since 2.7.0.
Some of the more significant enhancements include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.7.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.7.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.7.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.7.0 This is a bug fix and enhancement release, which requires a minimum of Java 8.
Some of the more significant enhancements include:
 Browser launch included by default - this allows you to launch browsers from ZAP that are preconfigured to proxy through ZAP and ignore the certificate warnings due to the ZAP root certificate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.6.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.6.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.6.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.6.0 This release contains a large number of changes, in particular to the ZAP API.
We have added a significant number of new API endpoints, working towards our goal of making ZAP completely controllable via the API. We have also changed some of the existing endpoints and in all cases these changes are backwards compatible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.5.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.5.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.5.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.5.0 The following changes were made in this release:
ZAP API Changes: VIEW authorization / getAuthorizationDetectionMethod Now returns data wrapped in an object called authorizationDetectionMethod For example:
{&amp;#34;authorizationDetectionMethod&amp;#34;:{&amp;#34;statusCode&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;-1&amp;#34;...&amp;#34;headerRegex&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;}} instead of:
{&amp;#34;statusCode&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;-1&amp;#34;...&amp;#34;headerRegex&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;&amp;#34;} VIEW context / context + technologyList Both now return data wrapped in an object called &amp;ldquo;context&amp;rdquo; For example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.4.3</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.3/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.4.3 The following changes were made in this release:
Enhancements:  Issue 1576 : Define URL path elements as &amp;rsquo;non structural&#39; Issue 1711 : Feature request: Option to specify number of token to be generated. Issue 1768 : Update to use a more recent user-agent Issue 1894 : ZAP only scans &amp;ldquo;User-Agent&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Referer&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Host&amp;rdquo; request headers Issue 1911 : Search AJAX spider requests Issue 1913 : Pass all params across to zap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.4.2</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.2/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.4.2 The following changes were made in this release:
Enhancements:  Issue 1306 : Java PermSize command line flag removed in Java 8 Issue 1593 : Auto-scroll in Spider tab Issue 1600 : Dont report X-Frame-Options alert on 403 and 404 pages Issue 1654 : httpSessions/createEmptySession should initialize a site that was not previously visited Issue 1702 : Add &amp;ldquo;recurse&amp;rdquo; option to the spider API Issue 1715 : Unable to pass arguments when launching ZAP from the command line on Mac OS X Issue 1766 : Remove context via the API Issue 1768 : Update to use a more recent user-agent Issue 1778 : Passive scan AJAX spider requests Issue 1790 : Move Buffer Overflow Scanner from Beta to Release Issue 1793 : Allow active scan scripts to check if the scan was stopped Issue 1795 : Allow JVM options to be configured via GUI Issue 1799 : Minor Feature Request: Allow URL to be pasted into start Spider dialog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.4.1</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.1/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.4.1 This release includes important security fixes - users are urged to upgrade asap.
One of the changes means that an API key is created by default, which means that any applications using the ZAP API will fail unless they are updated to use that key.
The API Key can be found in the API Options screen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.4.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.4.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.4.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: Attack mode A new &amp;lsquo;ATTACK&amp;rsquo; Mode has been added - new nodes that are in Scope are actively scanned as soon as they are discovered.
Advanced fuzzing A completely new fuzzing dialog has been introduced that allows multiple injection points to be attacked at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.3.1</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.3.1/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.3.1 The following changes were made in this release:
 Issue 81 : ZAP changes request data (while switching views) Issue 377 : Unfulfilled dependencies hang the active scan Issue 1073 : Cant remove scripts marked as &amp;rsquo;load on start&#39; Issue 1114 : core.newSession doesn&amp;rsquo;t clear Sites Issue 1155 : Historical Request Tab Doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow formatting changes Issue 1156 : Proxy gzip decoder doesn&amp;rsquo;t update content length in response headers Issue 1163 : Unable to set a home directory with a space on the command line Issue 1166 : Redundant indexes in zapdb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.3.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.3.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.3.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: ZAP ‘lite’ version For this release we are providing a ‘lite’ version of ZAP in addition to the ‘full’ version. This contains exactly the same core code, but it just includes fewer default add-ons. Of course, you can download all of the ‘missing’ add-ons from the ZAP marketplace to ‘upgrade’ the lite version to a full one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.2.2</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.2.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.2.2/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.2.2 The following changes were made in this release:
Minor changes: Issue 744 : Allow overwriting custom fuzz files Issue 795 : Allow param types scanned to be configured via UI Issue 797 : Limit number of ascan results listed to speed up scans Issue 798 : Add example scripts Bug Fixes: Issue 656 : Content-length: 0 in GET requests Issue 680 : Set the right content type for JSON API results Issue 716 : ZAP flags its own HTTP responses Issue 746 : PassiveScan Extension Crashes if the History Extension is disabled Issue 747 : Error opening session files on directories with special characters Issue 791 : Saved sessions are discarded on ZAP&amp;rsquo;s exit Issue 792 : Diff dialog fails when invoked from Zest Issue 794 : Malformed Byte Sequence Exception Issue 800 : User not prompted with check-for-updates option Issue 802 : XML report generated by API differs from GUI report See also            Introduction the introduction to ZAP    Releases the full set of releases    Credits the people and groups who have made this release possible    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.2.1</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.2.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.2.1/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.2.1 The following changes were made in this release:
Bug Fixes: Issue 789 : Scripting broken on Windows See also            Introduction the introduction to ZAP    Releases the full set of releases    Credits the people and groups who have made this release possible    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.2.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.2.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.2.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Major changes: Issue 717 : Scripts: support multiple scripts and embedding within ZAP components Support for Mozilla Zest: https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Zest Support for Mozilla Plug-n-Hack: https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Plug-n-Hack Support for scanning headers as well as JSON and XML formats Minor changes: Issue 711 : Support scanning of XML requests Issue 713 : Add CWE and WASC numbers to issues Issue 719 : Custom http breakpoints with more options Issue 738 : Options to hide tabs / windows Issue 750 : Upgrade script console to support non textbased scripting languages Issue 752 : Create a new root CA when first run Issue 775 : Allow host to be set via the command line Bug Fixes: Issue 555 : Http panels default to hex view Issue 599 : The save session api does not allow to overwrite session already has same name Issue 630 : URLCanonicalizer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.1.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.1.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Minor changes: Issue 355: Allow Positional Fuzzing Issue 475: Http Sessions custom cookie value Issue 484: Check java version in zap.sh Issue 496: Allow to see the request and response at the same time in the main window Issue 505: Http Session API Implementation Issue 515: Change add-ons to make use of automatic load of messages Issue 516: Change add-ons messages keys to have unique prefix Issue 518: Add OData support Issue 537: Option to Force Browse files/resources with user-defined extensions Issue 538: Allow non sequential lines to be selected in the history log Issue 542: browse api - prompt window to enable Issue 551: Add csrfmiddlewaretoken to list of default Anti csrf tokens Issue 552: Make ZapPortNumberSpinner a subclass of ZapNumberSpinner Issue 553: Add option to filter alerts by scope Issue 561: Copy URLs right click option Issue 566: Abstract class for creating generic popups Issue 568: Allow extensions to run from the command line Issue 569: Allow Spider Scan to start without prior visit Issue 587: Upgrade to JBroFuzz 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 2.0.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/2.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/2.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 2.0.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: An integrated add-ons marketplace ZAP can be extended by add-ons that have full access to all of the ZAP internals. Anyone can write add-ons and upload them to the ZAP Add-on Marketplace (OK, so its a Google code project called zap-extensions, but you get the idea).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.4.1</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.4.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.4.1/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.4.1 The following changes were made in this release:
Bug fixes: Issue 185: Problem causes Undoing/Redoing in text fields other than the one that has the focus. Issue 297: Exclusions not honored Issue 298: Content-Length header is not properly update Issue 306: Change zap.sh memory setting Issue 307: ConcurrentModificationException when openning a big session Issue 308: ZAP in daemon mode exits when you save a session Issue 309: Client API cant cope with Informational risk Issue 312: Increase the maximum number of scanning threads allowed Issue 314: Handle very large results more cleanly Issue 315: XSS false positive - injecting into an input src when the type is not &amp;lsquo;image&amp;rsquo; Issue 319: Spider progress not reported correctly via the API Issue 320: AScan can miss subtrees if invoked via the API Issue 337: Increase jvm permsize See also            Introduction the introduction to ZAP    Releases the full set of releases    Credits the people and groups who have made this release possible    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.4.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.4.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.4.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: Issue 133: Add Syntax highlighting to Response Panel The HTML panels now support switchable syntax highlighting.
Issue 153: fuzzdb integration The fuzzer includes fuzzdb (https://github.com/fuzzdb-project/fuzzdb) fuzzing files.
Note that some fuzzdb files have been left out as they cause common anti virus scanners to flag them as containing viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.3.4</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.4/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.3.4 The following changes were made in this release:
Minor changes: Issue 146: Inverse regex on search plus fuzz match highlighting Issue 202: Option to turn off brute force recursion Issue 215: Allow custom brute force files to be added easily Also added the ability to set the default brute force file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.3.3</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.3/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.3.3 The following changes were made in this release:
Bug fixes: Issue 156: ZAP active scanner freezes against DVWA Issue 157: Alert edit/save broken Issue 161: Reporting does not work when not specifying the extension in the report&amp;rsquo;s name (on Linux) See also            Introduction the introduction to ZAP    Releases the full set of releases    Credits the people and groups who have made this release possible    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.3.2</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.2/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.3.2 The following changes were made in this release:
Bug fixes: Issue 53: Scan Policy configuration bug Issue 62: The &amp;ldquo;Export all urls to File&amp;rdquo; does not seem to work Issue 87: SSL not working with Dynamic SSL Certificate generator (with Chrome on Mac OS) Issue 95: NullPointerException when dropping requests in proxy Issue 106: Cannot display HTTP gzipped contents Issue 107: The last intercepted request/response remains in the Break window Issue 131: Right click on Mac without mouse doesn&amp;rsquo;t work Issue 138: Broken end of stream detection causes endless loop and threads not ending Issue 143: Help button: Options &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Language Issue 145: Crash at start up Issue 147: Session save and request/response data Issue 151: Incorrect language used by ZAP Issue 152: Check for updates not working See also            Introduction the introduction to ZAP    Releases the full set of releases    Credits the people and groups who have made this release possible    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.3.1</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.1/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.3.1 The following changes were made in this release:
Bug fixes: Issue 97: Working Directory for Applications Issue 98: Not possible to cancel check for updates Issue 100: Alerts tab has 2 &amp;lsquo;Resend&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click popups Issue 104: Display warning dialog, when no root CA certificate exists Issue 110: Choosing user&amp;rsquo;s language by default, when starting the first time Issue 112: Provide a way to apply language packs on Mac OS Issue 121: Session compare report javascript broken in Firefox 3 Issue 123: Cant select https site from Active scan window if theres an http equivalent Issue 127: CSRF token feature does not work in fuzz - added help explanation for partial fix Issue 140: The Display options shouldnt include the advanced or windows manager options SSL Bug which prevented SSL connections from being established in any browser Known issues: Mac OS X: Dynamic SSL and Google Chrome Currently Dynamic SSL is not working when using Google Chrome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.3.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.3.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.3.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: Fuzzing Strings in a response can now be fuzzed to try to find vulnerabilities.
Anti CRSF tokens can be detected and automatically regenerated when fuzzing.
This functionality is based on code from the OWASP JBroFuzz project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.2.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.2.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.2.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: Memory Leaks Memory leaks have been fixed in the active scanner and spider.
Invoke applications External applications can now be invoked from the Sites and History tabs.
Passive Scanner The passive scanner now looks for vulnerabilities, such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.1.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.1.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.1.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: OWASP rebranding ZAP has been accepted as an OWASP project.
Its homepage is now: https://owasp.org/www-project-zap/
Brute Force The ability to brute force files and directories based on code from the OWASP DirBuster project.
The new Brute Force tab shows the files and directories found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release 1.0.0</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/releases/1.0.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/releases/1.0.0/</guid>
      <description>Release 1.0.0 The following changes were made in this release:
Significant changes: Help screens Help screens have been added for all of the functionality now provided by ZAP.
Context sensitive help has also been implemented so that when you press the F1 key then the help screen associated with the tab you have selected will be displayed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
