<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Tabs on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Tabs on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sites tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/sites/</guid>
      <description>Sites tab The sites tab contains two trees, one for Contexts and the other for the Sites Tree.&#xA;Contexts tree Shows the contexts contained in the current session. It allows to quickly access its properties by double clicking them and provides access to other functionality through the component&amp;rsquo;s context menu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Request tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/request/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/request/</guid>
      <description>Request tab The Request tab shows you the data sent by your browser for the request that you have highlighted in either the Sites tab or the History tab.&#xA;The top panel shows the request header and the bottom panel shows any data also sent, for example as a result of a POST request.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/response/</guid>
      <description>Response tab The Response tab shows you the data sent to your browser for the request that you have highlighted in either the Sites tab or the History tab.&#xA;Pull downs allow you to select different Views for the Response header and body.&#xA;Note that images are only shown in the History tab if the &amp;lsquo;Enable Image in History&amp;rsquo; flag in the View menu is selected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Break tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/break/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/break/</guid>
      <description>Break tab The Break tab allows you to change a request or response when it has been caught by ZAP via a breakpoint.&#xA;It allows you to change elements that you would not normally be able to change via your browser, including:&#xA;The header Hidden fields Disabled fields Fields that use javascript to filter out illegal characters This functionality is key to effectively pen testing your application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/history/</guid>
      <description>History tab The History tab shows a list of all of the requests in the order in which they were made.&#xA;For each request you can see:&#xA;The request index - each request is numbered, starting at 1 The HTML method, e.g. GET or POST The URL requested The HTTP response code A short summary of what the HTTP response code means The length of time the whole request took Any Alerts on the request Any Notes you have added to request Any Tags on the request Selecting a requests will display it in the Request tab and Response tab above.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/search/</guid>
      <description>Search tab The Search tab allows you to search for regular expressions in all of the URLs, requests, responses, headers and in other functionalities provided by add-ons.&#xA;Enter the regular expression you would like to search for in the search box and either press return or click on the search button: A pull down allows you to choose whether to search across the URLs, the requests, the responses or everything.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakpoints tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/breakpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/breakpoints/</guid>
      <description>Breakpoints tab The Breakpoints tab shows you all of the breakpoints that you have set.&#xA;Breakpoints can be set via the History and Sites tabs as well as the &amp;lsquo;Add a custom HTTP breakpoint&amp;rsquo; button on the top level toolbar&#xA;Right click menu Right clicking on a breakpoint will bring up a menu which will allow you to:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alerts tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/alerts/</guid>
      <description>Alerts tab The Alerts tab show the Alerts that have been raised in this session. The alerts are displayed in a tree in risk order in the left hand pane, and each node of the tree shows the total number of alerts underneath it.&#xA;Selecting an alert with one click will display it in the right hand pane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Scan tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/ascan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/ascan/</guid>
      <description>Active Scan tab The Active Scan tab allows you to perform an active scan.&#xA;The &amp;lsquo;Scan Policy Manager&amp;rsquo; button shows the Scan Policy Manager dialog which allows configuration of scan policies.&#xA;The &amp;lsquo;New Scan&amp;rsquo; button launches the Active Scan dialog which allows you to specify exactly what should be scanned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Params tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/params/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/params/</guid>
      <description>Params tab This shows a summary of the parameters and response header fields a site uses. Sites can be selected via the toolbar or the Sites tab.&#xA;For each parameter you can see:&#xA;The type - Cookie, FORM, URL, or Header The name of the parameter (or response header) The number of times it has been used The number of unique values The percentage change, where 0 means only one value has been used and 100 means all values are unique The flags - including cookie flags and anticsrf and session Some of the values - the full set of values may not all be visible Right click menu Right clicking on a node will bring up a menu which will allow you to:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spider tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/spider/</guid>
      <description>This page was moved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Sessions tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/httpsessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/httpsessions/</guid>
      <description>HTTP Sessions tab This tab shows you the set of identified HTTP sessions for each Site, as detected by the HTTP Sessions extension.&#xA;The current Site the information is referring to can be selected via the toolbar or the Sites tab.&#xA;The toolbar provides a button (&amp;ldquo;New Session&amp;rdquo;) which allows you to start a new session, forcing all outgoing request messages to be without the session tokens set, so the server considers it&amp;rsquo;s a new session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Output tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/output/</guid>
      <description>Output tab This show various informational messages.&#xA;These can include the stack traces of unexpected exceptions - please include any stack traces if you report a bug.&#xA;Right click menu Right clicking on a node will bring up a menu which will allow you to:&#xA;Copy This will copy the selected string to the clipboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Callbacks tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/callbacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tabs/callbacks/</guid>
      <description>Callbacks tab This tab shows a summary of the callback requests ZAP has received. For each callback you can see:&#xA;An Id The Timestamp of the received request. The Method associated with the request (GET, POST, etc.) The URL The Handler - The ZAP component which caught or responded to the callback request.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
