<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WebSockets on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WebSockets on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>WebSocket tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/tab/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket tab The WebSockets tab displays all messages from WebSocket connections. While ZAP is active, visit e.g.: Mozilla&#39;s BrowserQuest to see WebSockets in action.
Filters Channel Selector You can restrict the display of messages to one specific WebSocket channel or all.
If you select a specific channel, then the Show handshake button () becomes enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebSocket specific options</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/options/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket specific options This screen allows you to configure the WebSocket options:
Forward all If you&#39;re not interested in WebSockets communication, but you want to allow its messages being sent back &amp;amp; forth through ZAP, then you should enable this option. As a result no message will be stored in the session database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebSocket specific session properties</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/sessionproperties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/sessionproperties/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket specific session properties Exclude from WebSocket This allows you to manage the URLs where WebSocket communication is not processed in ZAP.
Although all messages from excluded URLs are forwarded, nothing is stored nor can you view them in the user interface. This feature is useful for high volume, performance critical WebSocket connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebSocket Scripts</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/script/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket Scripts WebSocket Sender WebSocket Sender scripts are called before forwarding the WebSocket message frame to the server or client and can access and change any WebSocket message that is proxied via ZAP.
They are initially disabled, to enable them right click the relevant script in the Scripts tree and select &amp;ldquo;enable&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebSocket API</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/api/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket API Views channels Returns all of the registered web socket channels.
message Mandatory Parameters:
 channelId: the channel identifier messageId: the message identifier  Returns full details of the specified message.
The &amp;lsquo;channelId&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;messageId&amp;rsquo; can be discovered via the &amp;lsquo;messages&amp;rsquo; view.
messages Optional Parameters:
 channelId: the channel identifier start: the offset to start returning messages from, starting from 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebSocket Passive Scan Rules</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/pscanrules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/pscanrules/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket Passive Scan Rules Scripts Scripts which are included by default in the add-on and they implement the following WebSocket passive scan rules:
Base64 Disclosure This script analyzes incoming WebSocket message payload for Base64 strings. The encoded information may include sensitive data which may not specifically meant for end user consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Sockets - About</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/websockets/about/</guid>
      <description>Web Sockets - About Source Code https://github.com/zaproxy/zap-extensions/tree/main/addOns/websocket
Authors ZAP Dev Team
History Version 19 - 2019-06-07  Fix exceptions when handling/dispatching events. Add wrapper to websocket API responses. Fix exception when handling API request with no API implementor. Correct output stream used in server mode. Add support for &amp;lsquo;other&amp;rsquo; API operations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>