<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Script Console on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Script Console on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scripts Automation Framework Support</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/automation/</guid>
      <description>Scripts Automation Framework Support This add-on supports the Automation Framework.&#xA;Job: script The script job allows you to execute various actions with scripts:&#xA;Action: add Adds the specified script to ZAP. Scripts are enabled but not configured to be loaded when ZAP restarts.&#xA;By default the default script engine for the file extension (if any) will be used - this may be overridden using the &amp;rsquo;engine&amp;rsquo; parameter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Script Console Tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/console/</guid>
      <description>Script Console Tab The Scripts Console allows you to write scripts which run within ZAP.&#xA;It is made up of:&#xA;A toolbar A text area (top) in which you can write your scripts An output text area (bottom) for debug and error messages, with &amp;ldquo;print&amp;rdquo; statements. To create a new script or to load or switch scripts see the The Scripts &amp;rsquo;tree&amp;rsquo; tab.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Script Console Options</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/options/</guid>
      <description>Script Console Options When the Script in the Console Changes on Disk This setting allows you to configure the default behaviour when a script open in the Script Console changes on disk, for example if it was updated in another code editor. There are three options to choose from:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Script Scan Rules</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/scanrules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/scanrules/</guid>
      <description>Script Scan Rules Active and Passive Scripts that implement the `getMetadata` function are treated as first-class scan rules by ZAP. Example implementation of this function in a script would look like:&#xA;function getMetadata() { return ScanRuleMetadata.fromYaml(` id: 12345 name: Active Vulnerability Title description: Full description solution: The solution references: - Reference 1 - Reference 2 category: INJECTION # info_gather, browser, server, misc, injection risk: INFO # info, low, medium, high confidence: LOW # false_positive, low, medium, high, user_confirmed cweId: 0 wascId: 0 alertTags: name1: value1 name2: value2 otherInfo: Any other Info status: alpha `); } The category field is only used for Active Scan Scripts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scripts tree tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/script-console/tree/</guid>
      <description>Scripts tree tab The Scripts tree tab shows you all of the scripts you currently have loaded organized by type.&#xA;It also shows you which templates you have available - these cannot be run directly, you use them to create new scripts.&#xA;It also allows you to add new scripts, load, save and remove them.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
