<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CWE-565 on ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/cwe-565/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CWE-565 on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/alerttags/cwe-565/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Poisoning</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10029/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10029/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This check looks at user-supplied input in query string parameters and POST data to identify where cookie parameters might be controlled. This is called a cookie poisoning attack, and becomes exploitable when an attacker can manipulate the cookie in various ways. In some cases this will not be exploitable, however, allowing URL parameters to set cookie values is generally considered a bug.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Loosely Scoped Cookie</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90033/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cookies can be scoped by domain or path. This check is only concerned with domain scope.The domain scope applied to a cookie determines which domains can access it. For example, a cookie can be scoped strictly to a subdomain e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nottrusted.com&#34;&gt;www.nottrusted.com&lt;/a&gt;, or loosely scoped to a parent domain e.g. nottrusted.com. In the latter case, any subdomain of nottrusted.com can access the cookie. Loosely scoped cookies are common in mega-applications like google.com and live.com. Cookies set from a subdomain like app.foo.bar are transmitted only to that domain by the browser. However, cookies scoped to a parent-level domain may be transmitted to the parent, or any subdomain of the parent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
