<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consulting on ZAP</title>
    <link>/successtags/consulting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consulting on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/successtags/consulting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SkypLabs</title>
      <link>/success/skyplabs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/skyplabs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SkypLabs is an Ireland-based company providing a wide range of IT services&#xA;globally, including security reviews and penetration testing. Created in 2021,&#xA;we have since worked with many different organisations to help them build and&#xA;secure their work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ZAP is our main tool when conducting web application penetration tests,&#xA;and we also use it when analysing the web trafic of desktop and mobile&#xA;applications. Besides its versatility and &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/burp-to-zap-feature-map/#burp-missing-features&#34; title=&#34;Burp Missing Features - ZAP Documentation&#34;&gt;unique features compared to&#xA;competitors&lt;/a&gt;, as being a company focusing on open-source&#xA;and user-respecting software, we love being able to contribute to projects&#xA;that share our values. We have, for instance, added the possibility to &lt;a href=&#34;/blog/2023-09-08-ds-store-parsing/&#34; title=&#34;Parsing .DS_Store files with ZAP - The ZAP Blog&#34;&gt;probe&#xA;and parse &lt;code&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/code&gt; files&lt;/a&gt; to automatically discover new&#xA;resources on a website with &lt;a href=&#34;/docs/team/kingthorin/&#34; title=&#34;Rick Mitchell - ZAP Team&#34;&gt;kingthorin&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s help, and the ability of&#xA;searching into notes (that we use a lot during security engagements).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Possible Security</title>
      <link>/success/possiblesecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/possiblesecurity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At Possible Security, we deliver specialized, expert-driven cybersecurity services to high-profile clients across industries. Our focus areas include penetration testing, red teaming, premium audits, and consulting. Based in Riga – the capital of Latvia and the jewel of Northern Europe – we are one of the few market leaders in the field – serving government institutions, critical infrastructure providers, and private sector clients with complex security needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clue Security Services AG</title>
      <link>/success/clue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/clue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ZAP tool is a significant asset to &lt;a href=&#34;https://clue.ch/&#34;&gt;Clue&lt;/a&gt;, as it is utilized on a daily basis by our security engineers. For the efficient design of a resilient WAF security policy, it is vital to reverse engineer the data flow of an application. ZAP offers an easy way to make the data flow transparent, to visualize the attack surface, and to develop tailor-made policies to minimize it. ZAP is also regularly used in application security consulting. Whether it is to develop and demonstrate a proof of concept for a found code vulnerability, to test an implemented application security function or just to have a function report which is used for threat modeling of an existing function. It is a pleasure to work with ZAP, which we use as a multi-tool for a variety of tasks related to application security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
