<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bar Charts</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/bar-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/bar-charts/</guid>
      <description>We measure and record a range of statistics related to ZAP, some of which are made public here.
The blog post: Collecting Statistics for Open Source Projects explains how this all works.
Check for Updates The number of Check for Update requests received per month. From 2.9.0 the suffix &amp;#39;d&amp;#39; indicates ZAP is running as a daemon rather than the desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highest False Positives Last Month</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/highest-false-positives-last-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/highest-false-positives-last-month/</guid>
      <description>These were the alerts most frequently flagged as false positives using Alert Filters last month.
Note that this does not necessarily mean they are false positives, it could mean that the people using ZAP are not interested in these specific vulnerabilities.
Position Alert Status Rule Type 1 Timestamp Disclosure release Passive 2 Cross-Domain JavaScript Source File Inclusion release Passive 3 Backup File Disclosure beta Active 4 Absence of Anti-CSRF Tokens release Passive 5 X-Frame-Options Header Not Set release Passive 6 Incomplete or No Cache-control Header Set release Passive 7 X-Content-Type-Options Header Missing release Passive 8 Information Disclosure - Suspicious Comments release Passive 9 User Agent Fuzzer beta Active 10 CSP release Passive 11 User Controllable HTML Element Attribute (Potential XSS) beta Passive 12 Path Traversal release Active 13 Cookie No HttpOnly Flag release Passive 14 Modern Web Application beta Passive 15 Content Security Policy (CSP) Header Not Set beta Passive 16 Strict-Transport-Security Header beta Passive 17 PII Disclosure beta Passive 18 Source Code Disclosure - File Inclusion beta Active 19 Cookie without SameSite Attribute release Passive 20 SQL Injection release Active </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pie Charts</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/pie-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/pie-charts/</guid>
      <description>Some stats are shown for all pings and for desktop only pings. The desktop pings show a significantly different profile, possibly because many automated ZAP scans run in the cloud and many cloud providers are located in the USA. We also know that quite a few companies run ZAP as a SaaS offering which will also skew the stats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top ZAP Add-Ons Last Month</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/top-addons-last-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/top-addons-last-month/</guid>
      <description>These were the most frequently installed optional add-ons last month.
Note that this does not mean they were the most used add-ons - that is harder to quantify.
Position Add-On Status Id Last Updated 1 Import/Export beta exim 2022-07-20 2 Passive scanner rules (beta) beta pscanrulesBeta 2022-04-05 3 Active scanner rules (beta) beta ascanrulesBeta 2022-06-08 4 Port Scanner beta portscan 2021-10-07 5 Access Control Testing alpha accessControl 2021-10-07 6 Sequence alpha sequence 2021-10-07 7 Plug-n-Hack Configuration beta plugnhack 2021-10-07 8 Passive scanner rules (alpha) alpha pscanrulesAlpha 2021-12-01 9 Requester alpha requester 2022-05-10 10 Active scanner rules (alpha) alpha ascanrulesAlpha 2022-04-08 11 Custom Payloads alpha custompayloads 2021-10-07 12 Advanced SQLInjection Scanner beta sqliplugin 2021-10-20 13 Wappalyzer - Technology Detection release wappalyzer 2022-08-15 14 FuzzDB Files release fuzzdb 2021-10-07 15 Directory List v2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
