<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Scan Rule Stats Last Month</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/active-scan-rules-last-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/active-scan-rules-last-month/</guid>
      <description>This page shows the statistics for the top 30 (by alert count) Active Scan rules last month. You can sort on any column - just click on the column headers.
For more details on what the stats mean see the blog post: Monthly Active Scan Rule Statistics
Alert Status Alert Count False Positive % Average Time in Secs User Agent Fuzzer release 38328789 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Charts</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/bar-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/bar-charts/</guid>
      <description>We measure and record a range of statistics related to ZAP, some of which are made public here.
The blog post: Collecting Statistics for Open Source Projects explains how this all works.
Check for Updates The number of Check for Update requests received per month. From 2.9.0 the suffix &amp;#39;d&amp;#39; indicates ZAP is running as a daemon rather than the desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highest False Positives Last Month</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/highest-false-positives-last-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/highest-false-positives-last-month/</guid>
      <description>These were the alerts most frequently flagged as false positives using Alert Filters last month.
Note that this does not necessarily mean they are false positives, it could mean that the people using ZAP are not interested in these specific vulnerabilities.
Position Alert Status Rule Type 1 Information Disclosure - Suspicious Comments release Passive 2 Cross-Domain Misconfiguration release Passive 3 X-Content-Type-Options Header Missing release Passive 4 Retrieved from Cache release Passive 5 Strict-Transport-Security Header release Passive 6 Loosely Scoped Cookie release Passive 7 User Agent Fuzzer release Active 8 Timestamp Disclosure release Passive 9 Session ID in URL Rewrite release Passive 10 Absence of Anti-CSRF Tokens release Passive 11 Content Security Policy (CSP) Header Not Set release Passive 12 CSP release Passive 13 Cross-Domain JavaScript Source File Inclusion release Passive 14 Anti-CSRF Tokens Check beta Active 15 Re-examine Cache-control Directives release Passive 16 Backup File Disclosure beta Active 17 Modern Web Application release Passive 18 Cookie No HttpOnly Flag release Passive 19 Anti-clickjacking Header release Passive 20 Permissions Policy Header Not Set beta Passive </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pie Charts</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/pie-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/pie-charts/</guid>
      <description>Some stats are shown for all pings and for desktop only pings. The desktop pings show a significantly different profile, possibly because many automated ZAP scans run in the cloud and many cloud providers are located in the USA. We also know that quite a few companies run ZAP as a SaaS offering which will also skew the stats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top ZAP Add-Ons Last Month</title>
      <link>/docs/statistics/top-addons-last-month/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/statistics/top-addons-last-month/</guid>
      <description>These were the most frequently installed optional add-ons last month.
Note that this does not mean they were the most used add-ons - that is harder to quantify.
Position Add-On Status Id Last Updated 1 Import/Export beta exim 2023-07-11 2 Requester beta requester 2023-07-11 3 Database alpha database 2023-07-11 4 Spider release spider 2023-07-11 5 Passive scanner rules (beta) beta pscanrulesBeta 2023-07-20 6 Authentication Helper beta authhelper 2023-07-11 7 Active scanner rules (beta) beta ascanrulesBeta 2023-07-20 8 Passive scanner rules (alpha) alpha pscanrulesAlpha 2023-07-20 9 Active scanner rules (alpha) alpha ascanrulesAlpha 2023-07-20 10 Access Control Testing alpha accessControl 2022-10-28 11 Port Scanner beta portscan 2022-10-27 12 Plug-n-Hack Configuration beta plugnhack 2022-10-27 13 Sequence alpha sequence 2021-10-07 14 Custom Payloads alpha custompayloads 2022-09-23 15 Advanced SQLInjection Scanner beta sqliplugin 2021-10-20 16 FuzzDB Files release fuzzdb 2022-09-23 17 Wappalyzer - Technology Detection release wappalyzer 2023-08-14 18 JWT Support alpha jwt 2023-01-02 19 Directory List v2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
