<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Selenium on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/selenium/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Selenium on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/selenium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Options Selenium screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/selenium/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/selenium/options/</guid>
      <description>Options Selenium screen This screen allows you to setup the requirements of some of the WebDrivers.
Configuration Options  WebDrivers     Field Details Default Config File     ChromeDriver This allows you to select the location of ChromeDriver. The path to the bundled WebDriver, if available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selenium API</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/selenium/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/selenium/api/</guid>
      <description>Selenium API The &amp;lsquo;selenium&amp;rsquo; API allows to set and view the paths to the required WebDrivers and binary.
API actions/views     Name Type Parameters Description     optionChromeBinaryPath view  Returns the current path to Chrome binary   optionChromeDriverPath view  Returns the current path to ChromeDriver   optionFirefoxBinaryPath view  Returns the current path to Firefox binary   optionFirefoxDriverPath view  Returns the current path to Firefox driver (geckodriver)   optionPhantomJsBinaryPath view  Returns the current path to PhantomJS binary   setOptionChromeBinaryPath action String* Sets the current path to Chrome binary   setOptionChromeDriverPath action String* Sets the current path to ChromeDriver   setOptionFirefoxBinaryPath action String* Sets the current path to Firefox binary   setOptionFirefoxDriverPath action String* Sets the current path to Firefox driver (geckodriver)   setOptionPhantomJsBinaryPath action String* Sets the current path to PhantomJS binary    Starred parameters are mandatory</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
