<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Options dialog on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Options dialog on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Options Active Scan screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ascan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ascan/</guid>
      <description>Options Active Scan screen This screen allows you to configure the active scan options:
Number of Hosts Scanned Concurrently  The maximum number of hosts that will be scanned at the same time. Increasing this may put extra strain on the computer ZAP is running on.
Concurrent Scanning Threads per Host  The number of threads the scanner will use per host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Active Scan Input Vectors screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ascaninput/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ascaninput/</guid>
      <description>Options Active Scan Input Vectors screen This screen allows you to configure the active scan input vectors.
These are the elements that the active scanner will attack.
Scanning all of the elements supported will take longer, but not scanning some elements may cause some vulnerabilities to be missed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Alerts screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/alert/</guid>
      <description>Options Alerts screen This screen allows you to configure the alerts options:
Merge related alerts in report  If selected then related issues will be merged in any reports generated.
This will significantly reduce the size of the report as duplicated information will be removed.
Max alert instances in report  The maximum number of alert instances to include in a report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Anti CRSF screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/anticsrf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/anticsrf/</guid>
      <description>Options Anti CRSF Tokens screen This screen allows you to configure the anti CSRF tokens options:
Tokens  The form POST parameter names that should be treated as anti CSRF tokens.
Partial Matches  Defines if the form POST parameter names should be treated as anti CSRF tokens if they include one of the tokens (instead of requiring an exact match).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options API screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/api/</guid>
      <description>Options API screen This screen allows you to configure the API options:
Enabled  If enabled then the API is available to all machines that are able to use ZAP as a proxy.
Web UI Enabled  If enabled then the API Web UI is available to all machines that are able to use ZAP as a proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Breakpoints screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/breakpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/breakpoints/</guid>
      <description>Options Breakpoints screen This screen allows you to configure the breakpoint options:
Confirm drop trapped message  Asks for confirmation when a request or response is dropped.
Only break on messages in scope  The &amp;lsquo;global&amp;rsquo; breakpoint will only be triggered by requests that are in scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Callback Address screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/callback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/callback/</guid>
      <description>Options Callback Address screen The Callback Address screen allows you to configure the address used to detect vulnerabilities that allow an attacker to call remote URLs.
In previous versions the ZAP API was used for this purpose, but from 2.6.0 onwards a separate endpoint is used so that target systems no longer need access to the API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Client Certificate screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/certificate/</guid>
      <description>Options Client Certificate screen The Client Certificate screen allows you to add a client certificate for ZAP to use when testing applications protected using mutual SSL. Currently supported ways to utilize certificates are PKCS12 and PKCS11.
Using PKCS12  It is possible to set the Client Certificate from the command line with the following switches:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Check for Updates screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/checkforupdates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/checkforupdates/</guid>
      <description>Options Check for Updates screen This screen allows you to configure whether ZAP checks to see if you are running the latest version when it starts, and if so what it does.
Check for Updates on startup  If selected then ZAP will automatically check for updates to the whole application and all of the add-ons when it starts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Connection screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/connection/</guid>
      <description>Options Connection screen The Options Connection screen allows you to configure the ZAP connection options:
Timeout (in seconds)  This makes is easier to test slow applications.
Default User Agent  The user agent that ZAP should use when creating HTTP messages (for example, spider messages or CONNECT requests to outgoing proxy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Database screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/database/</guid>
      <description>Options Database screen This screen allows you to configure the database options:
Compact (on exit)  Allows to compact the database when ZAP is closed, compacting the database ensures a minimal space disk usage but it will also take longer to exit ZAP.
Recovery Log  Controls whether or not database&amp;rsquo;s recovery log is enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Display screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/view/</guid>
      <description>Options Display screen The Display screen allows you to configure:
Images  If ZAP processes images.
Show (local) CONNECT requests  If the HTTP CONNECT requests received by the Local Proxies should be persisted in the current session and shown in the History tab. The default is to not show those requests, they happen frequently (in preparation for TLS/SSL, WebSocket&amp;hellip; connections) and, unless inspecting the behaviour of the client application, are not (usually) of much interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic SSL Certificates</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/dynsslcert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/dynsslcert/</guid>
      <description>Option Dynamic SSL Certificates OWASP ZAP allows you to transparently decrypt SSL connections. For doing so, ZAP has to encrypt each request before sending to the server and decrypt each response, which comes back. But, this is already done by the browser. That&amp;rsquo;s why, the only way to decrypt or intercept the transmission, is to do a &amp;lsquo;manipulator in the middle&amp;rsquo; approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Extensions screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ext/</guid>
      <description>Options Extensions screen This screen allows you to enable/disable extensions that are available to ZAP, either core or added by add-ons.
Enable/Disable Extensions  Enabled extensions will be loaded by ZAP, thus adding the functionalities provided by those extensions. Disabled extensions will not be loaded.
Core Extensions  Core extensions are extensions that if disabled will impair ZAP&amp;rsquo;s minimal functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Global Exclude URL screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/globalexcludeurl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/globalexcludeurl/</guid>
      <description>Options Global Exclude URL screen This screen allows you to configure the Global Exclude URL regexs in ZAP:
Regex  A regex of the URL that ZAP will ignore. Click the buttons Add, Modify, or Remove to edit each regex.
Enabled  If the box is checked, then this regex URL will be ignored by ZAP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options HTTP Sessions screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/httpsessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/httpsessions/</guid>
      <description>Options HTTP Sessions screen This screen allows you to configure the HTTP Sessions Extension&amp;rsquo;s options:
Default Tokens  These are the names of the Cookies that are considered by default to be session tokens. As soon they are detected as parameters on a Site, they are automatically added as session tokens for that Site, unless manually overriden by user command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options JVM screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/jvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/jvm/</guid>
      <description>Options JVM screen This screen allows you to configure the JVM options used when starting ZAP.
JVM Options  A free format text field which will be added to the Java command line call when invoking ZAP via either zap.sh or zap.bat.
The option was added so that the Java maximum memory allocation pool size can be set, which is of the form: -Xmxn where n is the size in bytes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Keyboard screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Options Keyboard screen This screen allows you to configure keyboard shortcuts for all of the ZAP menus.
Clicking on any of the table rows will bring up a dialog box which allows you to change the keyboard shortcuts.
&amp;lsquo;Action&amp;rsquo; Cheatsheet  Clicking on this button will generate an HTML page which shows all of the keyboard shortcuts sorted by &amp;lsquo;action&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options language screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/language/</guid>
      <description>Options language screen The language screen allows you to configure:
Language selection  The language ZAP uses for its display.
A set of languages are built into ZAP, however more languages may be available after the last release.
Check the ZAP download page for the latest language pack available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Local Proxies screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/localproxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/localproxy/</guid>
      <description>Options Local Proxies screen This screen allows you to configure the addresses and ports on which ZAP accepts incoming connections.
Local Proxy  By default ZAP will listen on one local address and port, and these are the address and port that you must configure your browser to use as a proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Passive Scan Rules Screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/pscanrules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/pscanrules/</guid>
      <description>Options Passive Scan Rules Screen This screen allows you to configure the passive scan rules.
Threshold  This controls how likely ZAP is to report potential vulnerabilities.
 If you select Off then the scanner won&amp;rsquo;t run. If you select Low then more potential issues will be raised which may increase the number of false positives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Passive Scan Tags screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/pscan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/pscan/</guid>
      <description>Options Passive Scan Tags screen This screen allows you to configure the tags that are added by the passive scanner. You can add, modify and remove the tags via the appropriate buttons.
Tag Interpolation  In order to allow some flexibility in Tag creation and content it is possible for the user to specify a regular expression with capturing groups which will be used to replace the group identifiers (ex: $1) in the resulting tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Passive Scanner Screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/pscanner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/pscanner/</guid>
      <description>Options Passive Scanner screen This screen allows you to configure the passive scanner.
Configuration Options     Field Details Default Config File     Only scan messages in scope Sets whether or not the passive scan should be performed only on messages that are in scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Rule Configuration screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ruleconfig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/ruleconfig/</guid>
      <description>Options Rule Configuration screen This screen allows you to configure the behaviour of specific active and passive scan rules.
Select any of the listed rows to see details of the specific configuration and to change the associated value. Both individual and all rules can be reset.
The built-in rules include:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Scripts screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/script/</guid>
      <description>Options Scripts screen This screen allows you to configure the script options:
Directories  A list of directories from which scripts will be loaded. ZAP will read (and write) the scripts using the character encoding UTF-8.
The scripts must be in subdirectories named after the relevant script type (such as &amp;lsquo;active&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;passive&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;proxy&amp;rsquo; etc) and must have an appropriate extension for the script language used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Search screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/search/</guid>
      <description> Options Search screen This screen allows you to configure the search options:
Maximum results show in &amp;ldquo;Search&amp;rdquo; tab  Allows to set the number of maximum results that should be show in the Search tab.
See also             UI Overview for an overview of the user interface    Options dialogs for details of the other Options dialog screens    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Spider screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/spider/</guid>
      <description>Options Spider screen This screen allows you to configure the spider options.
It should be noted that modifying most of these options also affects the running Spider.
Maximum depth to crawl  The parameter defines the maximum depth in the crawling process where a page must be found in order for it to be processed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Statistics screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/options/stats/</guid>
      <description>Options Statistics screen This screen allows you to configure the statistics that ZAP maintains.
In Memory Statistics Enabled  By default ZAP maintains the statistics in memory. To disable the in memory statistics uncheck this box.
Statsd Server Enabled  Check this box in order to configure the address of a Statsd server that ZAP will send its statistics to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
