<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GraphQL Support on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GraphQL Support on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Options</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/options/</guid>
      <description>GraphQL Options In this document, a &amp;lsquo;Query&amp;rsquo; may refer to a GraphQL query, subscription or mutation.
Maximum Query Depth The maximum depth of a generated query.
Lenient Maximum Query Depth If enabled, this option prevents invalid queries by allowing additional depth for fields with no leaf types. If disabled, Maximum Query Depth is enforced strictly, even if it means generating an invalid query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Support Script</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/script/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/script/</guid>
      <description>GraphQL Support Script The GraphQL Support script is responsible for two things:
Correctly representing the nodes for a GraphQL request in the sites tree (since ZAP 2.10.0). Adding GraphQL support for Active Scan Input Vectors. The following sections will elaborate a little on each of these functionalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Automation Framework Support</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/graphql-support/automation/</guid>
      <description>GraphQL Automation Framework Support This add-on supports the Automation Framework.
The add-on will import GraphQL schemas using introspection if endpoints are found while spidering. However, specifying an endpoint and (optionally) a schema file or URL is recommended if they are available.
Job: graphql The graphql job allows you to import GraphQL schemas locally or from a URL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
