<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authentication Helper on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authentication Helper on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Request Identification</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/auth-req-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/auth-req-id/</guid>
      <description>Authentication Request Identification This add-on includes a passive scan rule which attempts to identify authentication requests.
It identifies authentication requests by the presence of commonly used username and password field names. It also uses commonly used URL segments to identify more likely authentication requests, and uses commonly used registration URL segments to ignore registration requests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Detect Authentication</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/autodetect-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/autodetect-auth/</guid>
      <description>Auto-Detect Authentication This add-on adds a new authentication type which you can use to indicate that the Authentication Request Identification passive scan rule should attempt to configure the Authentication method automatically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Browser Based Authentication</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/browser-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/browser-auth/</guid>
      <description>Browser Based Authentication This add-on adds a new authentication type which uses a browser to login to the target website.
It uses the first field with a type of &amp;ldquo;text&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;email&amp;rdquo; for the user name and the first field with a type of &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; for the password.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Session Management Identification</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/session-mgmt-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/session-mgmt-id/</guid>
      <description>Session Management Identification This add-on includes a passive scan rule which attempts to identify session management methods.
It identifies session management methods by the presence of commonly used session management identifiers and any values specified in Authorization request headers.
The rule will not attempt to identify very unusual session management methods - automation is one of the end goals so false negatives (missing unusual session management methods) are more desirable than false positives (incorrectly identifying a session management method).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Detect Session Management</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/autodetect-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/autodetect-session/</guid>
      <description>Auto-Detect Session Management This add-on adds a new Session Management type which you can use to indicate that the Session Management Request Identification passive scan rule should attempt to configure the Session Management method automatically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Header Based Session Management</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/session-header/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/session-header/</guid>
      <description>Header Based Session Management This add-on adds a new session management type which supports an arbitrary number of headers.
If used in conjunction with Browser Based Authentication then it will also maintain all of the cookies set as part of authentication.
The header values can include the following tokens:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verification Request Identification</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/verification-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/verification-id/</guid>
      <description>Verification Request Identification This add-on includes a passive scan rule which attempts to identify Verification requests.
Verification requests are the requests that ZAP uses to tell if a session is still valid.
Unlike the other identification scan rules in this add-on, this rule will only raise alerts if you have indicated that you want to use verification auto-detection for a specific context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Tester Dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/auth-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/authentication-helper/auth-tester/</guid>
      <description>Authentication Tester Dialog This dialog allows you to test if ZAP can authenticate and automatically handle the session handling and verification for a site given only the login page and credentials.
Fields The following fields are provided:
Login URL The URL of the login page. It is mandatory and must start with &amp;ldquo;http://&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;https://&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
