<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Top Level Menu on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top Level Menu on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Analyse menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/analysis/</guid>
      <description>The Analyse menu This menu handles the scan policy.&#xA;The spider and scan options that were in this menu in an earlier version are now available via the Sites tab &amp;lsquo;Right click&amp;rsquo; menu.&#xA;Scan Policy Manager&amp;hellip; This displays the Scan Policy Manager dialog.&#xA;Note that add-ons can add additional menu items.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Edit menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/edit/</guid>
      <description>The Edit menu This menu handles finding strings in specific tabs, searching for strings across all requests and responses, changing ZAP&amp;rsquo;s mode, and managing forced user mode.&#xA;ZAP Mode This allows you to change the current mode.&#xA;Find&amp;hellip; This opens the Find dialog which allows you to find a string in the currently selected window.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The File menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/file/</guid>
      <description>The File menu This menu handles the current session. By default the following menu items will be present:&#xA;New Session This creates a new session.&#xA;If you have not saved your current session then a warning will be displayed.&#xA;Starting a new session without saving the current session will loose all of the data in the current session.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Help menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/help/</guid>
      <description>The Help menu This menu gives access to the &amp;lsquo;about&amp;rsquo; dialog and this help file.&#xA;About ZAP This displayed the &amp;lsquo;about&amp;rsquo; dialog.&#xA;Support Info&amp;hellip; Displays a dialog that contains information which is useful when troubleshooting or seeking support. Such as:&#xA;Version, installed add-ons and versions, operating system, java version, locale info, and ZAP Home Directory path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Import menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/import/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/import/</guid>
      <description> The Import menu This gives access to menus that allow to import data into ZAP.&#xA;Note that add-ons can add additional menu items.&#xA;See also The top level menu UI Overview for an overview of the user interface </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Online menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/online/</guid>
      <description> The Online menu This menu gives access to a set of online resources.&#xA;These links may be disabled if Java does not support opening URLs in a browser on your platform.&#xA;Note that add-ons can add additional menu items.&#xA;See also The top level menu UI Overview for an overview of the user interface </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Report menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/report/</guid>
      <description>The Report menu This menu handles the reports.&#xA;Compare with another Session&amp;hellip; This prompts you for a ZAP session that you have previously saved.&#xA;It then prompts you for an output file into which is written all of the URLs accessed by the current session and the session you have selected to compare it with.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tools menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/tools/</guid>
      <description> The Tools menu This menu handles the tools and general options.&#xA;Browse API Opens the ZAP API in the system&amp;rsquo;s default browser.&#xA;Options&amp;hellip;. This displays the Options dialog.&#xA;Note that add-ons can add additional menu items.&#xA;See also The top level menu UI Overview for an overview of the user interface </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The View menu</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/tlmenu/view/</guid>
      <description>The View menu This menu handles the display options.&#xA;Enable Image in History If selected then images will be displayed in the History tab.&#xA;Show Tab This allows you to show any of the tabs available, including those you have hidden.&#xA;Show All Tabs This allows you to show all tabs.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
