<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on ZAP</title>
    <link>/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZAP History: 2009 - Paros Proxy</title>
      <link>/docs/history/2009b-paros-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/history/2009b-paros-proxy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always had side projects but at that time I had never contributed to open source. I decided it was a good time to start contributing, so I looked around for an open source security tool with an active community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I couldn’t find one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OWASP had &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/OWASP/OWASP-WebScarab&#34;&gt;WebScarab&lt;/a&gt;, but I didn’t really get on with that, and in any case development on that seemed to have stopped.&#xA;The tool I most liked was called &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/paros/&#34;&gt;Paros Proxy&lt;/a&gt; - it was simple, effective and did what I needed. It was also written in Java so it wasn’t long before I pulled it into Eclipse and started making some tweaks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZAP History: 2009 - The Pentest</title>
      <link>/docs/history/2009a-the-pentest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/history/2009a-the-pentest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2009 I was a Java developer / team leader and led a small team which developed an online service for a major accounting software company.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As this service was considered to be security critical I insisted that an external pentest team was hired to ensure the software was suitably secure. To be honest I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too worried as we had seriously considered security throughout the process so I was fairly confident that the report would just show what a good job we had done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZAP History: 2010 - Andiparos</title>
      <link>/docs/history/2010b-andiparos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/history/2010b-andiparos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was still finalising the first ZAP release someone else beat me to it &amp;#x1f61f;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After years of being neglected, Paros was also forked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/axelneumann/&#34;&gt;Axel Neumann&lt;/a&gt; who called his version &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/archive/p/andiparos/&#34;&gt;AndiParos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit that I was very disheartened and seriously considered abandoning my plans for ZAP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZAP History: 2010 - Why the Name ZAP?</title>
      <link>/docs/history/2010a-why-the-name-zap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/history/2010a-why-the-name-zap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find naming things hard. It is easier if the tool has a very specific purpose, but ZAP has lots of uses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was a developer I always wrote command line scripts.&#xA;If I thought I might need them again then I would call them something sensible, something that would help me find them again.&#xA;But I also wrote one off scripts that I knew I would never use again. I always ended up calling those scripts “&lt;strong&gt;zap&lt;/strong&gt;” or “&lt;strong&gt;pow&lt;/strong&gt;” - think of cartoons: “ZAP! POW!”&#xA;I struggled with names for my fork of paros proxy and I kept on thinking of those two options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
