<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dialogs on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dialogs on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Scan dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/advascan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/advascan/</guid>
      <description>Active Scan dialog This dialog launches the active scanner.
Scope The first tab allows you to select or change the starting point.
If you have more that one scan policies then you will be able to select the one to use.
If the starting point is in one or more Contexts then you will be able to choose one of them.
If that context has any Users defined then you will be able to select one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan Policy Dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/scanpolicy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/scanpolicy/</guid>
      <description>Scan Policy Dialog This allows you to enable and disable the rules that are run when performing an active scan.
The first screen allows you to define the default levels as well as the levels for all of the rules in a specific category.
The category screens allow you to define the levels for every individual rule.
Note that passive scan rules are no longer managed via this dialog but are instead managed via the Options Passive Scan Rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Alert dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/addalert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/addalert/</guid>
      <description>Add Alert dialog This dialog allows you to manually add or change an Alert associated with a specific request.
Fields The dialog has the following fields:
Type The type of the alert is a pull down field which allows you to select one of a prepopulated set of issue types.
You can also enter your own text or change the text of one of the items you selected.
If you select one of the existing types then the Description, Solution and Other Info fields will be populated with text associated with the item you chose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add/Edit Breakpoint dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/addbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/addbreak/</guid>
      <description>Add/Edit Breakpoint dialog This dialogue allows you to add and edit HTTP breakpoints.
A breakpoint is defined by the following fields:
 Location - where the String is checked in the HTTP message: URL, Request Header, Request Body, Response Header, or Response Body. Match - how the String is interpreted, Regex or Contains, for regular expression or exact match, respectively, in the Location. The regular expression does not need to match the whole content of the Location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add Note dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/addnote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/addnote/</guid>
      <description>Add Note dialog This allows you to add a note to a request.
Accessed via            History tab &amp;lsquo;Note&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click menu item    See also            UI Overview for an overview of the user interface    Dialogs for details of the dialogs or popups    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encode / Decode / Hash dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/enc_dec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/enc_dec/</guid>
      <description>Encode / Decode / Hash dialog This allows you to encode, decode or hash text.
Common fields The dialog has one field that is common to all of the tabs:
Text to be encoded/decoded/hashed This field is for the text that you want to be encoded, decoded or hashed.
If any text is selected when the dialog is invoked then it will be put in this field. The other fields will be updated dynamically if you change the text</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/find/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/find/</guid>
      <description>Find dialog This allows you to find the text you enter in the selected tab.
Accessed via            Top level Edit menu &amp;lsquo;Find&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; menu item    Break tab &amp;lsquo;Find&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click menu item    Request tab &amp;lsquo;Find&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click menu item    Response tab &amp;lsquo;Find&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click menu item    Spider tab &amp;lsquo;Find&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click menu item    See also            UI Overview for an overview of the user interface    Dialogs for details of the dialogs or popups    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History Filter dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/hist_filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/hist_filter/</guid>
      <description>History Filter dialog This dialog allows you to restrict which requests are displayed in the History tab.
Fields The dialog has the following fields:
Methods The HTTP methods to filter on.
Codes The HTTP response codes to filter on.
Tags The Tags to filter on.
Alerts The types of Alerts to filter on.
Notes Whether the presence or absence of Notes should be filtered on.
URL inc regex A list of &amp;lsquo;include&amp;rsquo; regex patterns (one per line) - if specified then only those urls that match those patterns will be included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manual Request Editor dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/man_req/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/man_req/</guid>
      <description>Manual Request Editor dialog This dialog allows you to create a request from scratch which will be submitted to the specified target, or resend an existing request after making any changes to it that you want to.
Request tab This shows the request header and data, either in one or two panels depending on the options chosen.
A &amp;lsquo;Method&amp;rsquo; pull down allows you to switch between the HTTP methods.
Note that when the method is changed to a POST then any URL parameters are moved into the body, and when the method is changed from a POST then any parameters in the body are moved to the URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Add-ons</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/manageaddons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/manageaddons/</guid>
      <description>Manage Add-ons This allows you to manage the add-ons that you have installed and download new ones from the Add-on Marketplace.
Two tabs are available:
Installed This tab shows you the version of ZAP you are running, all of the installed add-ons and allows you to check for any updates to ZAP or any of the add-ons.
Hovering over an add-on will show you more information about it.
You can also uninstall add-ons from this tab - typically add-ons are dynamically removed from the ZAP UI as soon as you uninstall them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manage Tags dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/managetags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/managetags/</guid>
      <description>Manage Tags dialog This allows you to manage the tags associated with a request.
Accessed via            History tab &amp;lsquo;Manage Tags&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; right click menu item    See also            UI Overview for an overview of the user interface    Dialogs for details of the dialogs or popups    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persist Session dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/persistsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/persistsession/</guid>
      <description>Persist Session dialog This dialog is shown by default whenever you start a new session, which always happens when ZAP starts.
It allows you to specify how you would like this session persisted, you can also set the default choice so that you are not prompted again.
Persisting a session means it will be stored in a local database that you can access at a later date.
You do not need to keep &amp;lsquo;saving&amp;rsquo; a session as everything that happens in the session is continually recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan Policy Manager dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/scanpolicymgr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/scanpolicymgr/</guid>
      <description>Scan Policy Manager dialog This allows you to manage the scan policies that define the rules that are run when performing an active scan.
You can have as many scan policies as you like, and choose which one of them is run when you perform an active scan.
Add The Add button launches the Scan Policy dialog with all of the settings defaulted.
Modify The Modify button launches the Scan Policy dialog with all of the selected scan policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan Progress Dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/scanprogress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/scanprogress/</guid>
      <description>Scan Progress Dialog This shows you the status of an active scan.
Progress tab This shows which scan rules are running for each host being scanned, as well as other details such as the elapsed time they have been running and the number of requests made per rule.
It also allows you to skip the rule which is currently being run by clicking on the &amp;lsquo;Skip current running active scan&amp;rsquo; button in the Status column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spider dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/spider/</guid>
      <description>Spider dialog This dialog launches the spider.
Scope The first tab allows you to select or change the starting point.
If the starting point is in one or more Contexts then you will be able to choose one of them.
If that context has any Users defined then you will be able to select one of them.
If you select one of the users then the spider will be performed as that user, with ZAP (re)authenticating as that user whenever necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>