<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alert Filters on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alert Filters on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Alert Filters</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/contextalertfilter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/contextalertfilter/</guid>
      <description>Context Alert Filters Context Alert Filters allow you to automatically override the risk levels of any alerts raised by the active and passive scan rules within a context. The Alert Filters will be exported and imported with the context - they will not persist over ZAP sessions unless the context is imported again.
This add-on adds an &amp;lsquo;Alert Filters&amp;rsquo; panel to the contexts dialog.
The panel shows a list of all of the Alert Filters along with buttons for adding, removing, and deleting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Global Alert Filters</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/globalalertfilter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/globalalertfilter/</guid>
      <description>Options Global Alert Filters This Options screen allows you to configure Global Alert Filters which allow you to automatically override the risk levels of any alerts raised by the active and passive scan rules. Unlike Context Alert Filters they apply to all alerts raised, not just those raised in a specific context.
They will also be persisted across ZAP sessions.
The screen shows a list of all of the Global Alert Filters along with buttons for adding, removing, and deleting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alert Filter Dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/alertfilterdialog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/alertfilterdialog/</guid>
      <description>Alert Filter Dialog This dialog is shown when you add or modify a Context Alert Filter or a Global Alert Filter
It has the following fields:
Scope This can either be &amp;lsquo;Global&amp;rsquo; for a Global Alert Filter or the name of an existing context. It is only editable when you create an Alert Filter from an existing Alert.
Alert Type A pull down containing all of the active and passive alert rules currently installed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>