<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alert Filters on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alert Filters on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Context Alert Filters</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/contextalertfilter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/contextalertfilter/</guid>
      <description>Context Alert Filters Context Alert Filters allow you to automatically override the risk levels of any alerts raised by the active and passive scan rules within a context. The Alert Filters will be exported and imported with the context - they will not persist over ZAP sessions unless the context is imported again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options Global Alert Filters</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/globalalertfilter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/globalalertfilter/</guid>
      <description>Options Global Alert Filters This Options screen allows you to configure Global Alert Filters which allow you to automatically override the risk levels of any alerts raised by the active and passive scan rules. Unlike Context Alert Filters they apply to all alerts raised, not just those raised in a specific context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alert Filter Automation Framework Support</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/automation/</guid>
      <description> Alert Filter Automation Framework Support This add-on supports the Automation Framework.
Job: alertFilter The alertFilter job allows you to define global and context specific alert filters.
- type: alertFilter # Used to change the risk levels of alerts parameters: deleteGlobalAlerts: true # Boolean, if true then will delete all existing global alerts, default false alertFilters: # A list of alertFilters to be applied - ruleId: # Int: Mandatory alert rule id newRisk: # String: Mandatory new risk level, one of &amp;#39;False Positive&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Info&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Low&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Medium&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;High&amp;#39; context: # String: Optional context name, if empty then a global alert filter will be created url: # String: Optional string to match against the alert, supports environment vars urlRegex: # Boolean: Optional, if true then the url is a regex parameter: # String: Optional string to match against the alert parameter field parameterRegex: # Boolean: Optional, if true then the parameter is a regex, supports environment vars attack: # String: Optional string to match against the alert attack field attackRegex: # Boolean: Optional, if true then the attack is a regex evidence: # String: Optional string to match against the alert evidence field evidenceRegex: # Boolean: Optional, if true then the evidence is a regex </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alert Filter Dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/alertfilterdialog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/alert-filters/alertfilterdialog/</guid>
      <description>Alert Filter Dialog This dialog is shown when you add or modify a Context Alert Filter or a Global Alert Filter
It has the following fields:
Scope This can either be &amp;lsquo;Global&amp;rsquo; for a Global Alert Filter or the name of an existing context. It is only editable when you create an Alert Filter from an existing Alert.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
