<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ZAP Team on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ZAP Team on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs/team/psiinon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/team/psiinon/</guid>
      <description>Simon released ZAP in 2010 and has been working on it ever since.
Sponsor Simon&amp;rsquo;s work on ZAP is sponsored by Jit where he works as a Distinguished Engineer.
Expertise Simon has worked on nearly every part of the ZAP code base.
He is currently focusing on:
Automation Framework Test Scans Handling modern web apps more effectively Talks and Videos Simon has given ZAP talks at conferences all over the world and has recorded numerous videos, including the series:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs/team/thc202/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/team/thc202/</guid>
      <description>Ricardo started working on ZAP in 2011 and has made more PRs against the ZAP repos than anyone else.
Sponsor You can sponsor Ricardo directly via his GitHub Sponsor page.
He is also available for custom ZAP work.
Expertise Ricardo has worked on nearly every part of the ZAP code base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs/team/kingthorin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/team/kingthorin/</guid>
      <description>Rick started contributing to ZAP in 2014.
Sponsor Rick can be sponsored directly via his GitHub Sponsors page.
Other Work Rick is very active in OWASP and leads the Web Security Testing Guide and Vulnerable Web Applications Directory projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/docs/team/ricekot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/team/ricekot/</guid>
      <description>Akshath is the author of the GraphQL and OAST add-ons for ZAP.
He made his initial contributions as a Google Summer of Code student.
He loves hacking on ZAP and tries to contribute in whatever way he can - be it code, documentation or user support.
Sponsor Akshath can be sponsored directly via his GitHub Sponsors page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
