<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OWASP_2021_A02 on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/owasp_2021_a02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OWASP_2021_A02 on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/alerttags/owasp_2021_a02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Generic Padding Oracle</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90024/</guid>
      <description>By manipulating the padding on an encrypted string, an attacker is able to generate an error message that indicates a likely &amp;lsquo;padding oracle&amp;rsquo; vulnerability. Such a vulnerability can affect any application or framework that uses encryption improperly, such as some versions of ASP.net, Java Server Faces, and Mono. An attacker may exploit this issue to decrypt data and recover encryption keys, potentially viewing and modifying confidential data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP to HTTPS Insecure Transition in Form Post</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10041/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10041/</guid>
      <description>This check looks for insecure HTTP pages that host HTTPS forms. The issue is that an insecure HTTP page can easily be hijacked through MITM and the secure HTTPS form can be replaced or spoofed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS to HTTP Insecure Transition in Form Post</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10042/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10042/</guid>
      <description>This check identifies secure HTTPS pages that host insecure HTTP forms. The issue is that a secure page is transitioning to an insecure page when data is uploaded through a form. The user may think they&amp;rsquo;re submitting data to a secure page when in fact they are not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weak Authentication Method</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10105/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10105/</guid>
      <description>HTTP basic or digest authentication has been used over an unsecured connection. The credentials can be read and then reused by someone with access to the network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
