<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Success Stories on ZAP</title>
    <link>/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success Stories on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jit</title>
      <link>/success/jit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/jit/</guid>
      <description>OWASP ZAP has changed the adoption of security across the industry, enabling any organization to have better web application security through open source tooling. That is why after research and benchmarking Jit selected OWASP ZAP to be a critical tool in its DevSecOps orchestration platform. As a best of breed OSS DAST tool (dynamic application security testing), it provides development teams with the confidence in their application and API security, enabling them to deploy code at the velocity modern engineering organizations require.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla</title>
      <link>/success/mozilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/mozilla/</guid>
      <description>OWASP ZAP is integral to how Mozilla secures the services powering core Firefox features including Accounts, Addons, and Sync for millions of individuals around the world. We support the open source development of ZAP, because it helps us ensure the security and privacy of our users keeping the Internet a global, public resource open and accessible to all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>StackHawk</title>
      <link>/success/stackhawk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/stackhawk/</guid>
      <description>When we set out to build StackHawk, we wanted to help teams find and fix vulnerabilities before they deploy to production. As we were building our platform, we needed a scanner that worked for modern development teams. It needed to be easy to automate and be able to test modern single page apps and backing APIs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lombiq</title>
      <link>/success/lombiq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/lombiq/</guid>
      <description>ZAP now automatically scans our ASP.NET Core apps for each code change, and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with it.&#xA;We at Lombiq provide development, training, hosting, and consulting services for open source .NET-based technologies like the ASP.NET Core web CMS and framework Orchard Core. Our clients include Live Nation Clubs and Theaters, the Smithsonian Institution, and Microsoft itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clue Security Services AG</title>
      <link>/success/clue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/clue/</guid>
      <description>The OWASP ZAP tool is a significant asset to Clue, as it is utilized on a daily basis by our security engineers. For the efficient design of a resilient WAF security policy, it is vital to reverse engineer the data flow of an application. OWASP ZAP offers an easy way to make the data flow transparent, to visualize the attack surface, and to develop tailor-made policies to minimize it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Codific</title>
      <link>/success/codific/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/codific/</guid>
      <description>Codific is a developer of secure collaboration tools in Ed Tech, MedTech and HR Tech. Our team of software engineers leverages privacy by design and security by design principles to maximize the security of the applications and the privacy of its users.&#xA;Codific leverages a security assurance programme for all product development lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>we45 and AppSecEngineer</title>
      <link>/success/we45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/we45/</guid>
      <description>We at we45 and our training venture, AppSecEngineer use and train on ZAP extensively. We strongly believe OWASP ZAP to be the most programmable DAST tool in its class, regardless of commercial or OSS alternatives.&#xA;One of the things we do with our clients is to implement continuous DAST scanning as part of their DevSecOps initiatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Business Services</title>
      <link>/success/orange/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/orange/</guid>
      <description>At OBS, we strive continually to bring our customers peace of mind with strengthened and reinforced application security.&#xA;As part of automating our web application and API security, we chose to deploy OWASP ZAP as one of our Dynamic Application Security Testing (DAST) technologies. This DevSecOps approach helps our developers and engineering teams to detect vulnerabilities, including the OWASP Top Ten Web and API, in CI/CD pipelines before releasing our solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banzai Cloud</title>
      <link>/success/banzaicloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/banzaicloud/</guid>
      <description>At Banzai Cloud we use our dast-operator which leverages OWASP ZAP to run baseline scans against the services we deploy on the K8S cluster. This operator deploys OWASP ZAP to the K8S cluster and initiates automated security testing for web applications and APIs based on OpenAPI definitions. Besides the operator responsible for starting the scan against a service, it can prevent opening a vulnerable service to outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motorola Solutions</title>
      <link>/success/motorola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/success/motorola/</guid>
      <description>Motorola Solutions follows S-SDLC (secure software development lifecycle) best practices for our product development. Similarly, these best practices can be found in another OWASP project, the Software Assurance Maturity Model. We build our software development approach on the OWASP SAMM, to ensure delivery of secure products, from architecture design to the deployment in our own or customer’s infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
