<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation Framework on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation Framework on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - GUI</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/gui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/gui/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - GUI The Automation Framework has a GUI that is in the process of being developed.
Automation Tab This tab allows you to create, load, edit and run automation jobs. It has 2 sub tabs.
A toolbar provides the following buttons:
 New Plan&amp;hellip; - this launches the New Plan dialog Load Plan&amp;hellip; - this allows you to load a plan from a yaml file Save Plan&amp;hellip; - this saves the current plan to a yaml file Run Plan&amp;hellip; - this runs the current plan Add Job&amp;hellip; - this launches the Add Job dialog to add a job to the current plan Remove Job&amp;hellip; - this removes the selected job from the current plan Move Job Up - this moves the selected job up one place in the current plan Move Job Down - this moves the selected job down one place in the current plan Add Test&amp;hellip; - this launches the Add Test dialog to add a test to the current job Remove Test&amp;hellip; - this removes the selected test from the current job  Plan sub-tab A graphical representation of the plan which also shows the state of the plan when it is run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - Environment</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/environment/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - Environment This section of the YAML configuration file defines the applications which the rest of the jobs can act on.
The Automation Framework supports all of the authentication mechanisms supported by ZAP with the exception of scripts, which will be coming soon.
env: # The environment, mandatory contexts : # List of 1 or more contexts, mandatory - name: context 1 # Name to be used to refer to this context in other jobs, mandatory urls: # A mandatory list of top level urls, everything under each url will be included includePaths: # An optional list of regexes to include excludePaths: # An optional list of regexes to exclude authentication: method: # String, one of &#39;manual&#39;, &#39;http&#39;, &#39;form&#39; or &#39;json&#39; - script support is planned as well parameters: # All of the parameters support vars except for the port hostname: # String, only for &#39;http&#39; method port: # Int, only for &#39;http&#39; method realm: # String, only for &#39;http&#39; method loginPageUrl: # String, the login page URL to read prior to making the request, only for &#39;form&#39; or &#39;json&#39; methods loginRequestUrl: # String, the login URL to request, only for &#39;form&#39; or &#39;json&#39; methods loginRequestBody: # String, the login request body - if not supplied a GET request will be used, only for &#39;form&#39; or &#39;json&#39; methods verification: method: # String, one of &#39;response&#39;, &#39;request&#39;, &#39;both&#39;, &#39;poll&#39; loggedInRegex: # String, regex pattern for determining if logged in loggedOutRegex: # String, regex pattern for determining if logged out pollFrequency: # Int, the poll frequency, only for &#39;poll&#39; verification pollUnits: # String, the poll units, one of &#39;requests&#39;, &#39;seconds&#39;, only for &#39;poll&#39; verification pollUrl: # String, the URL to poll, only for &#39;poll&#39; verification pollPostData: # String, post dat to include in the poll, only for &#39;poll&#39; verification pollAdditionalHeaders: # List of additional headers for poll request, only for &#39;poll&#39; verification - header: # The header name value: # The header value sessionManagement: method: # String, one of &#39;cookie&#39;, &#39;http&#39;, &#39;script&#39; script: # String, path to script, only for &#39;script&#39; session management scriptEngine: # String, the name of the script engine to use, only for &#39;script&#39; session management users: # List of one or more users to use for authentication - name: # String, the name to be used by the jobs username: # String, the username to use when authenticating, vars supported password: # String, the password to use when authenticating, vars supported vars: # List of 0 or more custom variables to be used throughout the config file myVarOne: CustomConfigVarOne # Can be used as ${myVarOne} anywhere throughout the config myVarTwo: ${myVarOne}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - authentication</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/authentication/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - authentication The Automation Framework supports a subset of the authentication mechanisms supported by ZAP.
Environmental Variables ZAP supports a set of Authentication Header Environmental Variables - these will be applied by ZAP if they are defined however ZAP is run, including via the Automation Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - addOns Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-addons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-addons/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - addOns Job This job allows you to manage the ZAP add-ons.
The add-on identifiers to use in the &amp;lsquo;install&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;uninstall&amp;rsquo; lists are shown in the ZAP Desktop &amp;lsquo;Manage Add-ons&amp;rsquo; dialog or can be found on the ZAP Marketplace page.
YAML  - type: addOns # Add-on management parameters: updateAddOns: false # Currently disabled due to problems updating the framework and jobs while they are running install: # A list of non standard add-ons to install from the ZAP Marketplace uninstall: # A list of standard add-ons to uninstall </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - passiveScan-config Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanconf/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - passiveScan-config Job This job allows you to manage the passive scan configuration.
The passive scanner runs against all requests and responses that are generated by ZAP or are proxied through it. If you want to configure the passive scan configuration then you should typically do so before running any other jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - passiveScan-wait Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanwait/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanwait/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - passiveScan-wait Job This job waits for the passive scanner to finishing scanning the requests and responses in the current queue. You should typically run this job after the jobs that explore you application, such as the spider jobs or those that import API definitions. If any more requests are sent by ZAP or proxied through ZAP after this job has run then they will be processed by the passive scanner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - spider Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-spider/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - spider Job This job runs the traditional spider. This is fast but does not handle modern applications as effectively.
By default this job will spider the first context defined in the environment and so none of the parameters are mandatory.
YAML  - type: spider # The traditional spider - fast but doesnt handle modern apps so well parameters: context: # String: Name of the context to spider, default: first context user: # String: An optional user to use for authentication, must be defined in the env url: # String: Url to start spidering from, default: first context URL maxDuration: # Int: The max time in minutes the spider will be allowed to run for, default: 0 unlimited maxDepth: # Int: The maximum tree depth to explore, default 5 maxChildren: # Int: The maximum number of children to add to each node in the tree acceptCookies: # Bool: Whether the spider will accept cookies, default: true handleODataParametersVisited: # Bool: Whether the spider will handle OData responses, default: false handleParameters: # Enum [ignore_completely, ignore_value, use_all]: How query string parameters are used when checking if a URI has already been visited, default: use_all maxParseSizeBytes: # Int: The max size of a response that will be parsed, default: 2621440 - 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - activeScan Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-ascan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-ascan/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - activeScan Job This job runs the active scanner. This actively attacks your applications and should therefore only be used against applications that you have permission to test.
By default this job will actively scan the first context defined in the environment and so none of the parameters are mandatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - Job Tests</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/tests/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - Job Outcome Tests The automation framework supports testing the job outcomes based on conditions that you can set in the YAML file. Currently, tests of type &amp;lsquo;stats&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;alert&amp;rsquo; are available. More types will be added in the future.
Statistics Statistics-based tests are supported by all add-ons that have an automation job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - About</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/about/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - About Source Code https://github.com/zaproxy/zap-extensions/tree/main/addOns/automation
Authors ZAP Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - delay Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-delay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-delay/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - delay Job This job waits for a specified time unless one of a specific set of conditions are met.
It can be used to wait for regression tests being proxied through ZAP in order to explore your application more thoroughly.
The time parameter supports the formats hh:mm:ss, mm:ss and ss, so &amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; is 5 seconds, &amp;ldquo;1:30&amp;rdquo; is one minute and 30 seconds and &amp;ldquo;2:20:30&amp;rdquo; is 2 hours, 20 minutes and 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - requestor Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-requestor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-requestor/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - requestor Job This job sends specifically crafted requests to a target url, with a custom request method and body. The user can also specify an expected response code, against which the actual response is compared, and the user is warned in case it does not match.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
