<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation Framework on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation Framework on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - Environment</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/environment/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - Environment This section of the YAML configuration file defines the applications which the rest of the jobs can act on.
env: # The environment, mandatory contexts : # List of 1 or more contexts, mandatory - name: context 1 # Name to be used to refer to this context in other jobs, mandatory urls: # A mandatory list of top level urls, everything under each url will be included includePaths: # An optional list of regexes to include excludePaths: # An optional list of regexes to exclude authentication: # TBA: In time to cover all auth configs parameters: failOnError: true # If set exit on an error failOnWarning: false # If set exit on a warning progressToStdout: true # If set will write job progress to stdout vars: # List of 1 or more custom variables to be used throughout the config file myVarOne: CustomConfigVarOne # Can be used as ${myVarOne} anywhere throughout the config myVarTwo: ${myVarOne}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - addOns Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-addons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-addons/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - addOns Job This job allows you to manage the ZAP add-ons.
The add-on identifiers to use in the &amp;lsquo;install&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;uninstall&amp;rsquo; lists are shown in the ZAP Desktop &amp;lsquo;Manage Add-ons&amp;rsquo; dialog or can be found in the XML files which define the ZAP releases.
YAML  - type: addOns # Add-on management parameters: updateAddOns: true # Update any add-ons that have new versions install: # A list of non standard add-ons to install from the ZAP Marketplace uninstall: # A list of standard add-ons to uninstall </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - passiveScan-config Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanconf/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - passiveScan-config Job This job allows you to manage the passive scan configuration.
The passive scanner runs against all requests and responses that are generated by ZAP or are proxied through it. If you want to configure the passive scan configuration then you should typically do so before running any other jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - passiveScan-wait Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanwait/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-pscanwait/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - passiveScan-wait Job This job waits for the passive scanner to finishing scanning the requests and responses in the current queue. You should typically run this job after the jobs that explore you application, such as the spider jobs or those that import API definitions. If any more requests are sent by ZAP or proxied through ZAP after this job has run then they will be processed by the passive scanner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - spider Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-spider/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - spider Job This job runs the traditional spider. This is fast but does not handle modern applications as effectively.
By default this job will spider the first context defined in the environment and so none of the parameters are mandatory.
YAML  - type: spider # The traditional spider - fast but doesnt handle modern apps so well parameters: context: # String: Name of the context to spider, default: first context url: # String: Url to start spidering from, default: first context URL maxDuration: # Int: The max time in minutes the spider will be allowed to run for, default: 0 unlimited maxDepth: # Int: The maximum tree depth to explore, default 5 maxChildren: # Int: The maximum number of children to add to each node in the tree acceptCookies: # Bool: Whether the spider will accept cookies, default: true handleODataParametersVisited: # Bool: Whether the spider will handle OData responses, default: false handleParameters: # Enum [ignore_completely, ignore_value, use_all]: How query string parameters are used when checking if a URI has already been visited, default: use_all maxParseSizeBytes: # Int: The max size of a response that will be parsed, default: 2621440 - 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - activeScan Job</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-ascan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/job-ascan/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - activeScan Job This job runs the active scanner. This actively attacks your applications and should therefore only be used against applications that you have permission to test.
By default this job will actively scan the first context defined in the environment and so none of the parameters are mandatory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Framework - About</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/automation-framework/about/</guid>
      <description>Automation Framework - About Source Code https://github.com/zaproxy/zap-extensions/tree/main/addOns/automation
Authors ZAP Dev Team</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>