<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WSTG-v42-SESS-02 on ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/wstg-v42-sess-02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WSTG-v42-SESS-02 on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/alerttags/wstg-v42-sess-02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cookie No HttpOnly Flag</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10010/</guid>
      <description>A cookie has been set without the HttpOnly flag, which means that the cookie can be accessed by JavaScript. If a malicious script can be run on this page then the cookie will be accessible and can be transmitted to another site. If this is a session cookie then session hijacking may be possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Slack Detector</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90027/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90027/</guid>
      <description>Repeated GET requests: drop a different cookie each time, followed by normal request with all cookies to stabilize session, compare responses against original baseline GET. This can reveal areas where cookie based authentication/attributes are not actually enforced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie without SameSite Attribute</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10054/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10054/</guid>
      <description>A cookie has been set without the SameSite attribute, which means that the cookie can be sent as a result of a &amp;lsquo;cross-site&amp;rsquo; request. The SameSite attribute is an effective counter measure to cross-site request forgery, cross-site script inclusion, and timing attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie Without Secure Flag</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10011/</guid>
      <description>A cookie has been set without the secure flag, which means that the cookie can be accessed via unencrypted connections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Only Site</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10106/</guid>
      <description>The site is only served under HTTP and not HTTPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loosely Scoped Cookie</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90033/</guid>
      <description>Cookies can be scoped by domain or path. This check is only concerned with domain scope.The domain scope applied to a cookie determines which domains can access it. For example, a cookie can be scoped strictly to a subdomain e.g. www.nottrusted.com, or loosely scoped to a parent domain e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
