<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The OWASP ZAP Desktop User Guide on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The OWASP ZAP Desktop User Guide on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/desktop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Line</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/cmdline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/cmdline/</guid>
      <description>Command Line To run ZAP via the command line, you will need to locate the ZAP startup script.
Windows:
C:\Program Files (x86)\OWASP\Zed Attack Proxy\zap.bat Mac:
/Applications/OWASP\ ZAP.app/Contents/Java/zap.sh Linux:
zap.sh will be below the directory where ZAP was installed.
Alternatively, you can run the JAR file directly:
java -jar zap.jar All options below can be passed to any of these.
Options ZAP supports the following command line options:
           -version Reports the ZAP version    -cmd Run inline (exits when command line options complete)    -daemon Starts ZAP in daemon mode, ie without a UI    -config &amp;lt;kvpair&amp;gt; Overrides the specified key=value pair in the configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paros Proxy</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/paros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/paros/</guid>
      <description>Paros Proxy ZAP is a fork of version 3.2.13 of the open source variant of Paros developed by Chinotec Technologies Company.
The releases section details of the changes made to Paros.
The source code is freely and publicly available as required by the Clarified Artistic License under which Paros was released.
Changes to the software have been preceded by comments starting:
// ZAP:
Significant new functionality has been implemented in a separate tree under the package:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/credits/</guid>
      <description>Credits ZAP Core Team (Current) People who have made significant enhancements to the latest releases.
For more details of code contributions see: https://www.openhub.net/p/zaproxy/contributors
          Simon Bennetts (@psiinon) - Mozilla    thc202 - Sponsored by the Linux Foundation    Rick Mitchell (Kingthorin)    David Scrobonia (@david_scrobonia)    Sherif Mansour    ZAP Extended Team People who have made contributions to ZAP over the years, in alphabetical order:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>