<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OWASP_2017_A09 on ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/owasp_2017_a09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OWASP_2017_A09 on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/alerttags/owasp_2017_a09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Heartbleed OpenSSL Vulnerability</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/20015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/20015/</guid>
      <description>The TLS implementation in OpenSSL 1.0.1 before 1.0.1g does not properly handle Heartbeat Extension packets, which allows remote attackers to obtain sensitive information from process memory via crafted packets that trigger a buffer over-read, potentially disclosing sensitive information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heartbleed OpenSSL Vulnerability (Indicative)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10034/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10034/</guid>
      <description>The TLS and DTLS implementations in OpenSSL 1.0.1 before 1.0.1g do not properly handle Heartbeat Extension packets, which allows remote attackers to obtain sensitive information from process memory via crafted packets that trigger a buffer over-read, potentially disclosing sensitive information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Httpoxy - Proxy Header Misuse</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10107/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10107/</guid>
      <description>The server initiated a proxied request via the proxy specified in the HTTP Proxy header of the request.Httpoxy typically affects code running in CGI or CGI like environments. This may allow attackers to:&#xA;Proxy the outgoing HTTP requests made by the web application Direct the server to open outgoing connections to an address and port of their choosing or Tie up server resources by forcing the vulnerable software to use a malicious proxy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/40043-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/40043-1/</guid>
      <description>Apache Log4j2 &amp;lt;=2.14.1 JNDI features used in configuration, log messages, and parameters do not protect against attacker controlled LDAP and other JNDI related endpoints. An attacker who can control log messages or log message parameters can execute arbitrary code loaded from LDAP servers when message lookup substitution is enabled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Log4Shell (CVE-2021-45046)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/40043-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/40043-2/</guid>
      <description>It was found that the fix to address CVE-2021-44228 in Apache Log4j 2.15.0 was incomplete in certain non-default configurations. This could allow attackers to craft malicious input data using a JNDI Lookup pattern resulting in an information leak and remote code execution in some environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Code Execution - CVE-2012-1823</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/20018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/20018/</guid>
      <description>Some PHP versions, when configured to run using CGI, do not correctly handle query strings that lack an unescaped &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; character, enabling arbitrary code execution. In this case, an operating system command was caused to be executed on the web server, and the results were returned to the web browser.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Code Execution - Shell Shock</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10048-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10048-1/</guid>
      <description>The server is running a version of the Bash shell that allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Code Execution - Shell Shock</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10048-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10048-2/</guid>
      <description>The server is running a version of the Bash shell that allows remote attackers to execute arbitrary code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Script Served From Malicious Domain (polyfill)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10115-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10115-1/</guid>
      <description>The page includes one or more script files loaded from one of the &amp;lsquo;polyfill&amp;rsquo; domains. These are not associated with the polyfill.js library and are known to serve malicious content.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Script Served From Malicious Domain (polyfill)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10115-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10115-2/</guid>
      <description>The page includes one or more script which appear to include a reference to one of the &amp;lsquo;polyfill&amp;rsquo; domains. These are not associated with the polyfill.js library and are known to serve malicious content. You should check to see if it is a safe reference (for example in a comment) or whether the script is loading content from that domain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Source Code Disclosure - CVE-2012-1823</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/20017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/20017/</guid>
      <description>Some PHP versions, when configured to run using CGI, do not correctly handle query strings that lack an unescaped &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; character, enabling PHP source code disclosure, and arbitrary code execution. In this case, the contents of the PHP file were served directly to the web browser. This output will typically contain PHP, although it may also contain straight HTML.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring4Shell</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/40045/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/40045/</guid>
      <description>The application appears to be vulnerable to CVE-2022-22965 (otherwise known as Spring4Shell) - remote code execution (RCE) via data binding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text4shell (CVE-2022-42889)</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/40047/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/40047/</guid>
      <description>Apache Commons Text prior to 1.10.0 allows RCE when applied to untrusted input due to insecure interpolation defaults.Apache Commons Text performs variable interpolation, allowing properties to be dynamically evaluated and expanded.The application has been shown to initial contact with remote servers via variable interpolation and may well be vulnerable to Remote Code Execution (RCE).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable JS Library</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10003/</guid>
      <description>The identified library ExampleLibrary, version x.y.z is vulnerable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
