<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Session Properties dialog on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Session Properties dialog on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Context screens</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/contexts/</guid>
      <description>Session Context screens These screens allows you manage contexts.
There is a set of screens for each context you define.
Top screen This allows you to set the context name and description.
Include in Context This allows you to manage the URLs which will be included in the context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Context Authentication screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/context-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/context-auth/</guid>
      <description>Session Context Authentication screen This is one of the Session Context screens which allows you to manage the way in which Authentication is being done for the Context. After selecting the Authentication Method type, the options that need to be configured depend on the Authentication Method.
Note: Changing the authentication method after Users have been defined might cause its credentials to be reset, as the type of user credentials need to match the authentication scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Context Structure screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/context-struct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desktop/ui/dialogs/session/context-struct/</guid>
      <description>Session Context Structure screen This is one of the Session Context screens which allows you to manage ZAP&#39;s understanding of the structure of the application.
URL Key value pair separators The characters that separate pairs of keys and values in URLs, by default &amp;lsquo;&amp;amp;&#39;.
URL Key value separators The characters that separate keys and values in URLs, by default &amp;lsquo;=&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>