<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fuzzing on ZAP</title>
    <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fuzzing on ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo 0.125.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Options Fuzz screen</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/options/</guid>
      <description>Options Fuzzer screen This screen allows you to configure the fuzzing options:&#xA;Default Category The category that will initially be selected when the Fuzz dialog is displayed.&#xA;Add Custom Fuzz File Allows you to add your own files to be used when fuzzing.&#xA;These should be text files with one payload per line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzer dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/dialogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/dialogue/</guid>
      <description>Fuzzer dialog This allows you to select the fuzzers to use when fuzzing a request.&#xA;Fuzz Locations tab To configure the fuzzing:&#xA;Highlight a string you wish to fuzz in the Fuzz Locations tab Click the &amp;lsquo;Add&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; button to launch the Payloads dialog Add the payloads you want to use Click on the &amp;lsquo;Processors&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; button to launch the Location Processors dialog (if required) Click on the &amp;lsquo;Start Fuzzer&amp;rsquo; button to start the fuzzing The results will then be listed in the Fuzzer tab select them to see the full requests and responses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Message Processors</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/httpmessageprocessors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/httpmessageprocessors/</guid>
      <description>HTTP Message Processors HTTP Message Processors can access and change the HTTP messages being fuzzed, control the fuzzing process, and interact with the ZAP UI.&#xA;Built-in HTTP Message Processors include:&#xA;Anti-CSRF Token Refresher Allows to refresh anti-CSRF tokens contained in the request. The anti-CSRF tokens must be properly detected by ZAP to be able to use this processor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuzz Location Processors dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/locations/</guid>
      <description> Fuzz Location Processors dialog This allows you to select the payload processors to use with all payload generators.&#xA;The built-in payload processors included are the same that are available via the Payload Processors dialog.&#xA;Accessed via Fuzzer dialog &amp;lsquo;Processors&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; button See also Fuzzer concepts </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Payloads dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/payloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/payloads/</guid>
      <description>Payloads dialog This allows you to select the payload generators to use when fuzzing a request.&#xA;Payload generators generate the raw values or attacks that the fuzzer submits to the target application.&#xA;The following types of generators are provided by default:&#xA;Empty/Null - generates the selected payload multiple times, leaving the message without changes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Payload Processors dialog</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/processors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/processors/</guid>
      <description>Payload Processors dialog This allows you to select the payload processors to use with specific payload generators.&#xA;Built-in payload processors include:&#xA;Base64 Decode Base64 Encode Expand (to a minimum specified length) JavaScript Escape JavaScript Unescape MD5 Hash Postfix String Prefix String SHA-1 Hash SHA-256 Hash SHA-512 Hash Trim URL Decode URL Encode You can also write custom payload processor scripts - these can perform any manipulation of the payload that you need.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzer tab</title>
      <link>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/docs/desktop/addons/fuzzer/tab/</guid>
      <description>Fuzzer tab The Fuzzer tab shows you the requests and responses performed when you fuzz a message.&#xA;Select a row to see the full requests and responses. You can also search for strings in the fuzz results using the &amp;lsquo;Search&amp;rsquo; tab.&#xA;HTTP Fuzzer results The results have to be manually assessed to know if any vulnerability was found.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
