<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CUSTOM_PAYLOADS on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/custom_payloads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CUSTOM_PAYLOADS on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="/alerttags/custom_payloads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Application Error Disclosure</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/90022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/90022/</guid>
      <description>This page contains an error/warning message that may disclose sensitive information like the location of the file that produced the unhandled exception. This information can be used to launch further attacks against the web application. The alert could be a false positive if the error message is found inside a documentation page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous JS Functions</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10110/</guid>
      <description>A dangerous JS function seems to be in use that would leave the site vulnerable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden File Found</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/40035/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/40035/</guid>
      <description>A sensitive file was identified as accessible or available. This may leak administrative, configuration, or credential information which can be leveraged by a malicious individual to further attack the system or conduct social engineering efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Agent Fuzzer</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10104/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10104/</guid>
      <description>Check for differences in response based on fuzzed User Agent (eg. mobile sites, access as a Search Engine Crawler). Compares the response statuscode and the hashcode of the response body with the original response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Username Hash Found</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10057/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10057/</guid>
      <description>A hash of a username (admin) was found in the response. This may indicate that the application is subject to an Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) vulnerability. Manual testing will be required to see if this discovery can be abused.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
