<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OWASP_2017_A05 on OWASP ZAP</title>
    <link>/alerttags/owasp_2017_a05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OWASP_2017_A05 on OWASP ZAP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/alerttags/owasp_2017_a05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Absence of Anti-CSRF Tokens</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10202/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10202/</guid>
      <description>A cross-site request forgery is an attack that involves forcing a victim to send an HTTP request to a target destination without their knowledge or intent in order to perform an action as the victim. The underlying cause is application functionality using predictable URL/form actions in a repeatable way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cookie without SameSite Attribute</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10054/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10054/</guid>
      <description>A cookie has been set without the SameSite attribute, which means that the cookie can be sent as a result of a &amp;lsquo;cross-site&amp;rsquo; request. The SameSite attribute is an effective counter measure to cross-site request forgery, cross-site script inclusion, and timing attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cross-Domain Misconfiguration</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10098/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10098/</guid>
      <description>Web browser data loading may be possible, due to a Cross Origin Resource Sharing (CORS) misconfiguration on the web server</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directory Browsing</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/0/</guid>
      <description>It is possible to view the directory listing. Directory listing may reveal hidden scripts, include files, backup source files, etc. which can be accessed to read sensitive information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Path Traversal</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/6/</guid>
      <description>The Path Traversal attack technique allows an attacker access to files, directories, and commands that potentially reside outside the web document root directory. An attacker may manipulate a URL in such a way that the web site will execute or reveal the contents of arbitrary files anywhere on the web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permissions Policy Header Not Set</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10063/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10063/</guid>
      <description>Permissions Policy Header is an added layer of security that helps to restrict from unauthorized access or usage of browser/client features by web resources. This policy ensures the user privacy by limiting or specifying the features of the browsers can be used by the web resources. Permissions Policy provides a set of standard HTTP headers that allow website owners to limit which features of browsers can be used by the page such as camera, microphone, location, full screen etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Username Hash Found</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/10057/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 12:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/10057/</guid>
      <description>A hash of a username ({0}) was found in the response. This may indicate that the application is subject to an Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) vulnerability. Manual testing will be required to see if this discovery can be abused.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Actuator Information Leak</title>
      <link>/docs/alerts/40042/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 08:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/alerts/40042/</guid>
      <description>Spring Actuator for Health is enabled and may reveal sensitive information about this application. Spring Actuators can be used for real monitoring purposes, but should be used with caution as to not expose too much information about the application or the infrastructure running it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
